Hey, Gina,
you got that file
I needed Captain Holt
to sign?
Uh-huh.
ReEncoded By Dr.XJ | PSA
www.PSArips.com
Gina hasn't taken her eyes
off her phone in two hours.
First person to make her
look up wins the pot.
A bet which improves
someone's manners? Double score.
Sorry, guys.
I got this in the bag.
I used to have to distract her
from her phone
all the time
when we were smooshin' booties.
- Ugh.
- Yeah.
Hey, girl...
[grunts]
Catch you later.
Mid-morning
dance party.
[disco music playing]
She's dancing even better
than normal.
Oh, my God,
did you hear
that George W. Bush died?
Who dat?
[air horn blowing]
Gina may never look at another
real human being again.
She's unbeatable.
Oh, I don't know
about that.
Terrence Jeffords,
are you kidding me?
Changed my relationship status
to "it's complicated."
Pony up, y'all!
[Terry laughing]
Whoo!
[phone dinging]
- It's my wife.
Hey, baby.
No! No, no, no.
It was a mistake.
My thumb slipped and--
I have to go home.
[upbeat music]
♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
today is the greatest day
of my life.
Guess who just got murdered!
That's right--
it's Carl Mather.
[gasps dramatically]
What? I'm the only
one gasping?
Guys, Carl Mather?
Did 25 years in Attica--
[gasps dramatically]
Just point at me
when you want me to gasp.
Will do.
Mather is part
of the Fulton Street Four.
They stole $21 million
from an armored car depot.
Feds caught them
but they never found the money.
- Until now.
- You found $21 million?
Oh, God no.
Not yet.
I can see how that
would be confusing though.
I'm sorry.
But I'm going to.
all four of these guys
have been released,
and now one of them
shows up dead.
Someone's after that money,
and they're willing
to kill for it.
[gasps dramatically]
(Holt)
You're getting ahead of
yourself.
You don't know
that Mather's death
Don't turn this into something
bigger than it is,
not with Madeline Wuntch
watching us at all times.
Ew. When'd they put that in?
(Holt)
Right after Wuntch got promoted.
She had it installed
at that height so she'd,
I quote, "always be looking
down at me," unquote.
Treat this like a regular case.
Sir, with all due respect,
this is an epic case.
It's the reason I became a cop.
I mean,
hunting down a murderer,
recovering millions
in stolen money,
rappelling out of a chopper
with a knife between my teeth.
Why would you jump
out of a helicopter
with a knife
in your mouth?
It's called a chopper,
because both of my hands
are holding giant machine guns.
And that's how it's going down.
Okay, reminder,
tomorrow we are hosting
a field trip for
the Brooklyn Park Magnet School.
Sorry, Sarge, I can't be
around magnets.
I'm actually not gonna
correct you on that.
Guys, I really need this
to go well.
My girls are on the wait list
for their preschool
and it's twice as tough
to get in with twins.
and then let them take turns
going to school every other day?
Diaz, that's crazy.
I asked my wife
and she said no.
This field trip
has to go well.
This is my chance
to impress the principal.
Sarge, you're in luck.
I went to a magnet school
where I was voted
"most likely to befriend
a school administrator."
Oh, Amy.
Preteens
are my people.
I speak their language.
They are gonna have
an amazing time.
Thanks, guys.
That's great.
If you want, I can show them
some of the cool stuff
we have in the evidence locker.
I'm pretty sure
there's a bag of hands in there.
Whoa! No. No.
We got to make
this place kid-friendly.
No crime scene photos
lying about.
That's not a crime scene.
That's a boudoir photo
I'm having framed for my wife.
That's me underneath
the mask.
Oh, God!
[police radio mumbling]
(Jake)
Next, let's get statements
from the neighbors.
Quick update: another one
of the Fulton Street Four
Huh, I'm surprised you're
not celebrating inappropriately.
This is a crime scene
and I'm a professional.
You did it
before I showed up?
Yeah, that is
exactly correct.
So two of these guys murdered
in the past two days?
It has to be tied
to the missing money.
Admit I was right.
Circumstances do suggest
a connection.
- You were right.
- Yes! Did you get it, Boyle?
Oh, the camera
was in selfie mode,
Unfortunately, because this case
has turned out to be important,
that she-skunk
Madeline Wuntch
has her hindquarters
pointed right at it.
She wants to see us
in her office,
no doubt to give the case
to Major Crimes.
No, no, no.
We can't let that happen.
Sir, we have
to do something.
Fine.
I'll seduce her.
and give her a glimpse
of the quad cities.
No. No.
That's not what I meant.
I meant we have
to fight her.
We're not gonna fight her.
She's the devil.
And you don't dance
with the devil,
because you get
burned.
Also, because
in Madeline's case,
she has no rhythm
and her hands
are like little
rat claws.
If she wants the case,
it's hers.
For the record,
you're turning this murder scene
into a real bummer-scape.
Oh, the camera was in
selfie mode again,
but I was really
laughing hard.
Okay, kids, this is where my
detective squad solves crimes.
- Wow.
- This is my desk.
You can tell by the framed
200-piece puzzle
my three-year-olds
put together on their own.
That's very advanced,
Sergeant Jeffords.
Is it? I wouldn't know
what milestones
are impressive to a school
admissions officer.
They can count to 20
in English and Mandarin.
Hi. Detective Santiago,
magnet school
alumna.
Well, I appreciate
that you used
the proper declension
of alumnus.
Well, some say Latin
is a dead language,
but I say it's just
taking a long nap.
[all laughing]
(Gina)
Okay, you two are obviously
the alphas.
Let me guess.
You're dating
the blond kid
and you like
Filipino Bieber
but you're worried
he's still into
Little Miss Side Braid
Janky Purse.
How did you know?
[chuckles]
I know so much.
Hi, I'm Gina.
[chuckles]
Hey.
[clears throat]
Hello, Raymond.
How do you like
my new office? 20th floor.
Yes, I never thought
I'd see you this high
without a broom
under you.
Enough niceties.
Have a seat.
Thanks, but I'm actually
fine standing.
I could stay in these
bad boys all day.
So two members
of the Fulton Street Four
have been murdered--
sounds like a big case.
No, it's actually
the opposite.
Pretty much
an NBT sitch.
No big thang.
The word is "thing,"
and the thing is big.
We believe someone is after
the missing $21 million,
and solving this murder
could lead us to the money.
Sure, but that money's,
like, 25 years old.
It's probably not
even good anymore.
[grunts]
Sorry. Cramped up.
This is a very
important case, Raymond,
to me, and to the city
of New York.
I'm not sure the Nine-Nine
has the resources
to deal with something
of this magnitude.
I understand
the politics.
This is a
high-profile case.
Do what you must.
What I was going
to say is,
since you don't have
the resources,
I'll give you
anything you need.
The case is yours.
You have my full support.
He meant that more excited.
Like, "What!"
My hunch--one of them
is killing off his co-scums
so he can keep the money
for his scum-self.
We'll start with Reggie Bludsoe.
He listed a Brooklyn address
with his parole officer.
We're gonna nail
this son of a bitch.
then we're gonna have
the son of a bitch.
Either way, this case
is gonna be awesome.
Peralta, I'm putting myself
on this investigation with you.
- What? Why?
- Wuntch is up to something.
There's only one reason why
she would let us keep this case.
"That's the guy I want
flying my chopper."
You know how
to fly a chopper?
How hard could it be?
She let us keep this case
because she wants us to fail.
I'm coming along
so that you don't waste
time and resources
turning this investigation
into another
Ron McClane movie.
Oh, you know
it's John McClane.
I've made my decision.
End of discussion.
I signed out that drug dealer's
Lamborghini from the impound.
It only has two seats.
I saw that you had made
that request.
I changed it
to a sensible sedan.
Okay, but the sunroof
stays open.
There is no
sunroof.
Why did you even
become a cop?
Oh, great job, kids.
Don't solve too many crimes
and put me out of business.
Terry's got to pay the rent.
[laughs]
Dr. Susman wants
a private chat with me.
Thanks for warming her up,
Santiago.
They didn't give
eighth grade Amy
the key to the teacher's lounge
just for nothing.
I stocked their fridge
and cleaned up after them.
Great. So can you take over
with the kids for a minute?
They're done
with this activity.
Of course.
I am amazing with kids.
[laughs nervously]
Okay.
I haven't listened to rap music
in three years.
I don't know the lingo.
You have to do this.
I can't--McKenzie is
in the bathroom right now
freaking out because Kelsey S.
made out with Hayes
even though she knows
Brianna's into him.
So unless you want
the spring dance
to be a total
drama fest,
I have to be there
for her.
Honestly, you should show them
a picture of a dead body.
No! Rosa, Terry said
to keep it kid-friendly.
Okay, I'll just show them
the stuff that I was into
when I was their age.
- I'm done.
- What do we do now?
- What's next?
- Hello, friends.
Who here would like to see
a presentation
about crime statistics
as a function
of demographics and time?
Who wants to see
a picture of a dead body?
(all)
Me!
Bludsoe lives at the end
of his hall.
Hmm--I would have preferred
an abandoned lighthouse
or a dilapidated barn,
but I can embellish
in my memoirs.
Oh, I can't wait
to read that book.
What are you gonna
call it?
[in gravelly voice]
"Go Ahead, Jake My Day."
No, yours is much better.
"Case Closed, Jake Open."
- Wow.
- I know.
I said yours was better.
Whatever.
Let's just do this.
[pounding]
NYPD. Open up.
[clock clicking open]
Hey, check it out.
(Jake)
Half-packed suitcase.
Looks like Bludsoe
was planning a trip
until he got
interrupted by someone.
- Or something.
- Like what?
I don't know--I just thought
it would help the intrigue.
It did.
Come on, how many people
have to get killed
You do know it's our job
to stop the killing, right?
Wait a second.
[sniffs]
I think I smell
a dead body.
[sniffs]
[clears throat]
Nope. My mistake.
Wait! Don't close that.
(Jake)
Look. Handprint.
That's a fake wall.
NYPD.
Come out with your hands
on your head.
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot.
He's trying
to kill me.
So I guess, if I had
to sum them up,
Cagney is
the intellectual one,
whereas Lacey is more
of your traditional prodigy.
Well, your daughters
sound great.
You know, I'm gonna look over
their applications again.
Oh, no, that's not
necessary.
But what really matters
is that your students
have an amazing
experience here today.
They are.
Look, Rosa.
Sarge is here.
Oh, my God.
[shrieking horror music]
Children, get out
of this room immediately.
(whispering angrily)
What the hell, guys?
They're 12 years old.
I would've killed
to have seen
a bag of hands
at that age.
I'm so sorry--
I tired to be myself
- Where were you?
- Saving the day.
Hayes is out
of the picture.
The McKenzie/Kelsey S.
beef is squashed,
and Brianna's going
to the dance with Aidan,
who's a much better match
for her anyway, BT-dubs.
How does any of that help me?
- Dr. Susman--
- Good-bye, Sergeant Jeffords.
I think this experience
has been
more than enough
for the children.
We're done here.
I was walking home
from the coffee shop.
I have a job
bussing tables there.
Anyway, the next thing
I know,
Mikey D has a gun
in my back.
Michael D'Angelo,
the other member
Yes, believe it or not,
I familiarized myself
with the names
of all two suspects
in this high-profile homicide
we're investigating.
I fought him off,
but he got my key.
What's the key for?
Each of us had one,
and you needed all four
to open the safe.
And what's
in the safe?
The $21 million.
Bing--pot--
Nope--I was gonna say bingo,
but then it was too late;
I was halfway through the word.
Bingpot works.
It's taking off.
Captain, D'Angelo
has a place upstate.
The local sheriff says there's
a car in the driveway right now.
Okay, they're gonna have to
raid the place without us.
It'll take us two hours
to get up there.
Or we could take--
We are not taking
a helicopter.
You know I was
gonna say chopper.
Look, Peralta,
I know you're having fun,
but a helicopter
is exactly the kind
of wasteful expenditure
that Wuntch will use
to bury me
if something goes wrong.
- Okay, sir--
- Or...
It's the kind of thing
she'll crucify me
for not getting.
"You could've had
a chopper, Raymond.
"Why didn't you
take advantage?
Just a minute--
my cauldron's boiling over."
Yeah, but what
she actually said was,
[in Boston accent]
"Chopper's yours, Peralta."
Your impression
was better.
She may have called me
and I may have briefed her
because it's definitely
on its way right now!
I call middle seat!
This is awesome!
Okay, just so
we're clear,
from this point
forward,
my call sign
will be Death Blade.
And I'll be
Rum Tum Tugger.
No, Boyle.
No characters from Cats.
Dig deep.
Think of something scary.
Adolf Hitler.
No!
You will be...
Sidewinder.
All right, but I'm more scared
of Hitler.
How about you, Captain?
What's your call sign?
I will be
Captain Raymond Holt.
Uh-huh, I knew
you wouldn't play ball.
And that is why your call sign
is Wet Blanket.
Sidewinder,
this is Death Blade.
Do you copy, Sidewinder?
Over.
This is Sidewinder,
Death Blade.
I read you loud and clear.
Over.
Do you have a 20
on Wet Blanket, Sidewinder?
Over.
- I do have a visual--
- Over.
All right,
look, Captain,
Wuntch said that
we could have
anything we needed
to solve this case.
Yes, but why?
To catch a murder
who stole $21 million.
No, it's so that
when we do fail,
it'll be that much
more spectacular.
If we don't
get D'Angelo,
my career is over.
But if we do catch him,
your career will really
take off.
Chopper pun!
Dr. Susman,
I am so, so sorry.
Please don't hold this
against my daughters.
I would never
do that.
Preschool admissions
are based
on what we think
of the parents.
Oh, no.
Dr. Susman--
Nancy, if I may--
- You may not.
- Okay.
Look, our methods may have been
a little unorthodox,
and perhaps
a little--
Graphic and disgusting.
I was gonna go
with yucky...
But these kids
had fun today.
And they learned a lot.
Tricia,
what's Luminol?
It's used to look for blood
in a crime scene.
Even if a criminal
tried to clean it up,
the iron in blood
makes the chemical glow.
And, Bobby,
what's enucleation?
It's when someone
pops your eyeball out.
Probably should've used
a less gross example.
this is exactly the kind
of educational experience
I loved about my magnet school.
Well, there's something
to be said for that.
Also, and more importantly,
I got McKenzie and Brianna
to stop hating
on Kelsey S.
and now they're best friends--
you're welcome.
Wow, that's actually
impressive.
Thank you.
(Terry)
So, Dr. Susman,
let's just call this field trip
what it was--
a huge success.
It was...interesting.
(Bobby)
I saw a prostitute.
Not helping, kid.
[helicopter humming]
[upbeat hip-hop music]
♪
[slo-mo]
I'm Death Blade.
♪
D'Angelo's place
is just beyond those trees.
No one's gone in our out.
Good thing we got here
in time.
Flew in on a chopper.
Bell 412
or the A119 Koala?
It's classified.
Actually, it was
the 350B2.
(Jake whispering)
No, don't give him the "nice."
We haven't seen
any movement in the house,
but there are lights on
in the barn.
There's a barn?
What is your fascination
with barns?
It's where all the awesome
stand-offs happen--
rusty farm equipment, light
shining through bullet holes.
I'll bet you
at least one dove
I will take that bet,
because that's impossible.
We've got a team
on the back entrance,
a team watching the house,
Okay, tell your men
if they find the money first,
that I get to riffle it
next to my ear and go,
- Already told them, Jake.
- Love you, bud.
All right,
let's lock and load.
[suspenseful music]
♪
Dope.
[dove fluttering]
- [startles]
[sighs]
Moved faster
than I was expecting,
but still cool.
I don't see him.
Oh, he's here.
I can feel it.
He is.
He's dead.
- What?
- The body is right here.
Damn it!
Bludsoe played us.
[groans]
Pick up, pick up,
pick up.
- Hello?
- Hey, it's Peralta.
Is Bludsoe still in custody?
Yeah, we got him.
He's in his--
Ooh.
[groans angrily]
[clears throat]
So...good news first.
We're gonna be flying back
past a beautiful sunset.
Bad news--Bludsoe escaped
from the hospital
- [inhales angrily]
- But... Pretty sunset.
For him, that's like a full-on,
rage-fueled freak out.
The only thing worse is when
he stands perfectly still.
Oh, no, he's standing
perfectly still.
(Jake)
All right, I'm gonna go
talk to him.
Mm, no I'm not.
Yep, I am.
No, I'm not gonna do it.
Okay, I am.
I'm gonna go.
Okay.
Be careful.
- You're so brave.
- Thanks.
Hey, Captain.
Mostly about how Madeline Wuntch
will destroy me
because you wanted a helicopter
to play action movie.
I needed
the helicopter
because I was
chasing a bad guy
Really? It wasn't just
to make this case epic?
This case is epic.
You're just too wrapped up
in the politics to see it.
Sir, we're tracking
a triple murderer
who stole $21 million,
and all you can think about
is Madeline Wuntch.
[sighs]
- You're right.
- What's that now?
Before I came
to the Nine-Nine,
I was rotting away
behind a desk
All I wanted was the chance
to do good police work again.
I just got it,
and I blew it
thinking about
that devil toad.
I'm tired of politics.
Let's get that punk!
Bludsoe.
[gasps]
This is amazing.
Of course, we have no idea
where he is,
but I love where
your head's at.
He has no family.
or someone he worked with
at the coffee shop.
The coffee shop--
why would someone
who knows they have
$21 million coming
take a minimum wage job?
Because he needed
access to that building.
Because that's where
the money's hidden.
All right, we got
to get there quick.
Maybe we should
take the chopper.
[gasps]
You said chopper.
Death Blade,
Sidewinder,
it's go time!
Roger that, Wet Blanket.
No, from now on,
call me...
Velvet Thunder.
Okay.
Hey, Cagney and Lacey
got off the wait list.
Thank you, guys,
for helping me.
Rosa, I should've
listened to you.
Yeah, everyone should
listen to me
all the time
about everything.
It was pretty fun.
The kids actually liked me.
I wish I could go back
to middle school
knowing what I know now.
I'd be so cool.
And I'd get to retake
all the tests.
And update
some book reports.
Oh, un, Gina,
Dr. Susman said
you had a real impact
on those kids.
Apparently,
you were just named
Spring Dance Princess
somehow.
Mm-hmm, what am I
always telling you guys?
I'm royalty.
(whispering)
All right, listen up.
We go in strong
and we go in fast.
Evans, you're on
door breach.
Patterson--
flashbang.
Boyle, stop squatting
like that.
Sorry, I thought
it looked cool.
- It didn't.
- On the count of three.
[bangs]
- It's Bludsoe!
- NYPD!
- Go, go, go!
Facedown,
flat on the ground!
[men shouting]
- Hey, over here, over here.
[policeman shouting]
[door creaking]
Bingpot!
[cameras clicking]
This rules.
Did you know that my dream
has always been to have
my picture taken with a mountain
of recovered cash?
And it's always been
my dream
to take that picture
of you, Jake.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Yeah!
$21 million, Raymond.
I have to admit,
I'm impressed.
Sorry to disappoint you,
Madeline.
I know you'd hoped
we'd fail.
Oh, no, I couldn't
be happier.
Wait...
Why would you say that?
And why aren't you
clenching
your little rat hands
in anger?
You didn't want me
to fail.
You wanted me
to succeed.
I was looking for an excuse
to promote you to a desk job,
and you handed it to me
on a silver platter
with your little
rat hands.
Oh, no.
Say good-bye
to the Nine-Nine, Raymond.
I'm making you head
of NYPD Public Relations.
Captain,
get in here with me.
Go ahead.
Smile for the cameras, Raymond.
That's your new job now.
[cameras clicking]
Hey!
Okay, quick,
let's pose back-to-back
with our arms crossed
and a cocky smirk.
You doing it?
Your arms crossed?
No, arms down.
That's good.