This job is eating me alive.
I can't breathe anymore.
I spent all these years
trying to be the good guy.
The man in the white hat.
I'm not becoming like them.
I am them.
Hey! What are
you doing, weirdo?
I'm doing the best speech
from Donnie Brasco.
Or, actually...
Ten of me are doing the best
speech from Donnie Brasco.
What's up?
Get it together, man.
Okay?
So, the store was hit
about two hours ago.
They took mostly tablets,
laptops, and cameras.
Sorry.
I'd like a list of all your employees
who ever had access to the store.
I'd also like to apologize
for my partner.
His parents didn't
give him enough attention.
Uh... Detective?
I already solved the case.
We're looking for three white males, one
of whom has sleeve tats on both arms.
And how do you know that?
I had an informant
on the inside.
He's been here for years.
Watching, learning, waiting...
His code name...
Fuzzy Cuddle Bear.
He's a nanny cam.
Ugh! You got lucky.
No, I got here
five minutes before you
and figured that in this
gigantic electronics store
there had to be at least
one working camera.
Oh! Hi, bad guys.
You did it, Fuzzy.
You busted 'em.
It's time to come home.
I'm not sure if I can.
I've been undercover so long,
I've forgotten who I am.
I've seen terrible things.
I haven't known the touch
of a woman in many moons.
All right.
Detective Santiago?
Don't walk away from me!
Yes, I did crack the case.
So, Santiago,
would you do the honors?
- I hate this.
- Oh, yeah.
I hate this. And you're
just gonna wanna add one.
I'm winning!
It's a good feeling. It's
a good feeling. Yeah.
Enjoy it while it lasts.
I will.
J.P., update on the
Morgenthau murder?
Yeah. Good news for
all you murder fans.
Earlier this morning, someone
decided to shoot and kill
luxury food importer,
Henry Morgenthau.
Body was found by
the cleaning lady.
During her interview, I deduced
using expert detective work,
that she had something
super gross on her chin.
I think it was flan.
Charles thinks it was flan. I think
it was butterscotch pudding.
Maybe it was just old
person gunk.
You know how old people always
have that gunk on them?
Oldie gunk. Could be.
Yeah. Anyone else?
How about we focus
on the murder,
and not the old person gunk?
Crime techs are
at the scene now.
We're heading back
when they're done.
Okay.
I want you on this.
It's gonna be priority one
for the new CO.
Wait. Tell us about
the new captain.
Captain Holt will be here soon.
He'll want to introduce himself.
Dismissed.
Hey, Gina,
you know any scalpers?
I wanna ask Rosa to go to the
Rihanna concert with me,
but it's sold out.
Okay, two points to make here.
First, Rihanna?
You...
And then Rihanna.
Yeah. What's your second point?
She's got a type,
which is really anyone but you.
Yeah, that was my
ex-wife's type, too.
Look, a Rihanna concert
is a pretty big swing, man.
I don't know.
She's into watching old movies.
Cool!
Where would I find a place
that shows old movies?
Oh, yeah. Just go
on the Internet
and search for the phrase,
"I want to buy two movie tickets"
"for a girl
who doesn't like me."
Great. Thank you.
Good.
Hey, have you heard anything
about the new captain?
Uh, no, and I don't care.
I just wish Captain McGintley never left.
He was the best.
He was terrible.
You just liked him 'cause he let
you do anything you wanted.
On your marks, get set...
Go.
What the hell's goin' on
around here?
Fire extinguisher
roller chair derby.
Okay.
And go!
What's your point?
If I'm ever gonna make
captain, I need a good mentor.
I need my rabbi.
Sorry, dude. But this new guy's gonna
be another washed-up pencil pusher,
who's only concerned with
Following every rule
in the Patrol Guide.
Meep morp zeep!
Robot captain engage.
- Is that what you think?
- Hey!
New captain alert.
You must be the new CO.
I'm Detective Jake Peralta.
Great to meet you.
No, don't let me interrupt you.
You were describing what
kind of person I'm gonna be.
I'd like you to finish.
It's not necessary.
Or I could recap very quickly.
Sure. Um, let's see.
I think I said some joke about
being a washed-up
pencil-pusher.
Now do the robot voice.
The robot voice you were doing when you
implied I'm a rule-following robot.
I wanna hear it again.
Meep, morp, zarp.
Robot.
- That's a terrible robot voice.
- Yep.
The next time I see you, I'd like
you to be wearing a necktie.
Oh, uh, actually,
the last captain
didn't care if we wore ties.
Well, your new captain does.
And more importantly, he cares
that you follow his direct orders.
Everyone.
I'm your new Commanding
Officer, Captain Ray Holt.
Speech!
That was my speech.
Short and sweet.
Sergeant Jeffords.
A word.
Yes, sir.
I love that guy.
Same.
He's so suave.
Does anyone get a little
bit of a gay vibe?
No? Okay.
Sergeant, you were in
the One-Eight with me.
Though you were significantly...
Fatter, sir. They called
me Terry Titties.
Because I had large, uh...
Titties.
Yes. I remember.
I never liked that nickname.
Though to be fair,
it was accurate.
What's this I hear about you
being on administrative leave?
A year ago, my wife and I
had twin baby girls, uh...
Cagney and Lacey.
They have adorable
chubby cheeks.
Ever since, I kinda
got scared of getting hurt.
Lost my edge.
There was an incident
in a department store.
Hey, man. You okay?
You look a little jumpy.
Oh, I'm fine. I'm fine.
ReEncoded By Dr.XJ | PSA
www.PSArips.com
I think he's dead.
And I'm still not right.
Tell me about your
detective squad.
Um, well...
Scully, Hitchcock, and Daniels.
They're pretty much worthless.
But they make good coffee.
Copy that.
Now the good ones.
Rosa Diaz. Tough,
smart, hard to read,
and really scary.
Tell me who has me
for Secret Santa.
No! That takes all
the fun out of it.
It's Scully.
He got you a scarf.
I'll make him return it.
Yes, you will.
Charles Boyle.
He's a grinder. Not the
most brilliant detective,
but he works harder
than anyone else.
He's not physically
gifted.
Aw, man!
My muffin!
Ah!
Ow, my head!
My muffin and my head!
And I stepped on... On my muffin,
and my head and my muffin.
Amy Santiago.
She's got seven brothers.
So she's always trying
to prove she's tough.
Be careful.
That stuff's pretty hot.
Oh, is it? Hmm?
She and Peralta have some big bet
over who gets more arrests this year.
Ever since the bet, their
numbers have gone way up.
Tell me about Peralta.
Jacob Peralta is
my best detective.
He likes putting away bad guys
and he loves solving puzzles.
The only puzzle he hasn't solved
is how to grow up.
That was very well put.
I've talked a lot about
Jake in my
departmentally-mandated
therapy sessions.
Look, you know my history.
You know how important
this is to me.
This precinct is doing fine.
But I want to make it
the best one in Brooklyn.
And I need your help.
Absolutely, sir.
Where do we start?
What is happening?
We start with him.
Okay. So the perp came in through the
window, left the muddy red footprint,
and apparently had sex
with the dish rack.
Shell casings found here.
Two shots.
Bang, bang.
Great work, Detective.
You get a tie.
Hey, that's mine.
You took it from my desk.
That's right, Charles.
Good solve. Tie for you.
Thanks! Now everyone be sure
to put those on, because it's
impossible to solve crimes
unless you're wearing a tie.
Lay off the Captain.
That man is gonna be my rabbi.
Okay, first of all, when
you use the word rabbi,
you know that turns me on. And that's
unfair in the work environment.
Secondly, your rabbi
is a pain in my ass.
Yeah, he's a little too serious.
What do you think, Rosa?
Seems cool. Yeah, seems cool.
I agree.
Looks like the perp stole
a computer, a watch,
and a Jamón lbérico ham,
valued at... What?
$6,000.
$6,000 for a ham?
Jamón lbérico is an amazing
cured ham from Spain.
They had it at
my uncle's funeral.
I gorged myself at that funeral.
I mean, I was constipated
for three days.
Wow. That's a great
story, Charles. Thank you.
All right, listen up, everybody.
Better contact Captain Holt and let
him know we got a ten-tie situation.
Speaking of ties,
where's yours, Meep-Morp?
This is fantastic.
Captain! Hey!
Welcome to the murder.
What are you doing here?
I like to know what my
detectives are up to.
Is that okay by you?
Yep.
Take Santiago
and knock on doors.
See if the neighbors
heard anything.
Door duty?
It's a waste of time.
Diaz and Boyle, check in with the coroner.
Report back to me in an hour.
That went well.
No, it didn't.
He's got like, super hearing.
Hey, Rosa. Rosa, Rosa.
Um...
I just happened to notice that
there's an old movie festival
playing at the
Film Forum this week.
You want to go?
Sure.
Cool! Awesome.
There's a bunch
of movie options.
I'll probably just go
with something classic.
Like Citizen Kane.
Citizen Kane is terrible.
Pick a good movie.
Good call. Smart.
I'll do it. I'll pick
a better movie than
Citizen Kane.
So, Gina, civilian
administrators like yourself
often have their ear
to the ground.
What do Santiago and Peralta have
riding on this bet of theirs?
I will tell you
on six conditions.
Number one, you let me use your
office to practice my dance moves.
Second... How about this.
If you tell me...
Mmm-hmm? ...I won't
have you suspended
without pay.
Oh, that sounds great!
Okay, the deal is if Amy gets more
arrests, Jake has to give her his car.
It's an old Mustang.
It's pretty sweet.
If he gets more arrests, she
has to go on a date with him.
He guarantees
it will end in sex.
I'd bet on at least some
over-the-clothes action.
At the very least some touching.
Oh, that's enough, Gina.
Caresses...
I could see him showing
up in a silk robe...
That's enough, Gina.
All right.
Thank you.
Let the wasting of time begin.
Hello, sir.
May we ask you a few questions?
Definitely. Yeah.
I'm actually... I'm super glad
you guys are here right now.
Are you smelling
that weed smell?
Yeah.
'Cause a dude broke in, smoked
weed, and bolted. It's...
Do you think it's the same dude that
left that bong there on the floor?
Yes.
Police.
Hello. What's your name?
Hello.
My name? Mlepnos.
Mmm-hmm.
Can you spell that, please?
M-L-E-P...
Clay.
Did you say Clay?
Yes. The "Clay" is silent.
All right. Got it.
Have you seen this man before?
He was shot last night.
Oh!
Thank you.
No. Sir? That's ours.
We need that.
We...
And he kept it.
Wall Street Journal on the
doormat, top floor apartment.
20 bucks says this guy's like
a hot, eligible bachelor.
I'll take that action.
Police, open up.
Hello.
Hello, sir!
How are you today?
I am Detective
Right-All-The-Time,
and this is my partner,
Detective Terrible-Detective.
No surprises from the coroner.
Two gunshots,
shoulder and chest.
None of the neighbors
heard or saw anything.
And what's worse, Santiago
struck out with a 92-year-old.
That is not accurate, sir.
Wait, you hooked up
with him? Ugh!
All right. Hit the pawnshops
and canvas the neighborhood.
And while you're out,
you can buy yourself a tie.
Oh, actually, sir...
I'm wearing a tie right now.
Check it out!
Secret tie!
First of all, I think you're kind of
overdoing it with the manscaping.
But more importantly, Detective,
why do you refuse
to take my orders seriously?
Does anyone here know why
it's so important to me
that you all dress
appropriately?
Hmm. Four highly-trained detectives and not
one of you can solve this simple mystery.
Okay, I want to be briefed
on any new developments.
Any questions? I was gonna ask you
if you thought I was doing too much
manscaping, but we solved that
one, so I'm good. Mmm-hmm.
Hey, Boyle.
Yeah?
What about this fancy ham stuff?
Jamón lbérico?
Yes. The perp left
a really expensive TV,
but then stole ham?
It doesn't make sense.
Is there a place nearby the
crime scene that sells it?
Beneficio's might.
Let's go.
You're gonna brief the CO first.
We'll brief him after
we catch the guy.
My name is Ratko.
I don't know anything.
Oh.
Okay. You recognize
this guy?
Henry Morgenthau?
No.
Maybe, actually...
Look at the picture?
I don't know him.
I don't know what happened.
No more questions!
Well, why don't I run
a scenario past you, Ratko,
and you tell me what you think?
You do know Morgenthau. He came in
here and tried to sell you some hams.
You knew they were worth
a lot of money,
so you tried to steal them
from him when he wasn't home.
Only he was home,
so you shot him.
Does that sound familiar?
Uh, maybe some role-play
will jog your memory?
That's a great idea.
Okay. Yeah.
Uh, so I'm... I'm Ratko.
No, no. I'm Ratko.
Come on. I'm always the victim.
So...
Look, I'm not doing this
with you right here.
Fine. Fine.
Oh, I'm Henry Morgenthau, owner
of delicious and expensive hams.
Don't I know you from the
grocery store? Kill.
And scene.
NYPD. Everyone, down!
Ma'am, if you could
just get down.
Or ignore me
and continue shopping.
- Boyle, get the door!
- On it.
Ratko?
Back up.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Ow! Ratko!
I'm getting mad!
That's a waste of Manchego!
Charles!
How are you still here?
Jake! Little help?
Ratko!
We're not going anywhere, Jake.
I've got him. It's cool.
I got him.
He's all mine.
So, no, I did not brief you.
And, yes, he did get away.
But, some bonus good news.
I got you hazelnut.
And, little spoon there,
for you.
Is he seriously assigning
me to the records room?
I mean, why do we even
have a records room?
The computer has been invented, right?
I didn't dream it?
You're lucky, man.
I wish I could get
assigned here full time.
You could not be farther
from the action.
Sergeant, you know me.
I have more arrests than anyone.
Will you please tell the
Captain how dumb it is
to lock his best detective
in a file cabinet?
Second best.
You're wrong about Holt.
That man has forgotten more about
being a cop than you will ever know.
In 1981, he caught
the Disco Strangler.
It's over, Disco Man.
Put down the yo-yo and
back away from the girl.
Wow.
The man is the real deal.
You need to listen to him.
Going to be hard to win our bet
when you're on the bench, Peralta.
Although, I did start
a new category.
"Murderers we let go."
And look at that!
You're winning!
Have fun with your files.
Yeah. You know what? I will
have fun with my files.
Have fun with your face!
Slam!
That was a slam.
So? What movie did you
get us tickets to?
Oh, well, just to be safe,
I bought tickets to all of them.
Just to be safe?
What does that mean?
I don't know. Uh, I
didn't wanna mess up,
because you're
sort of opinionated.
You think I'm opinionated?
Okay, here's an opinion for you.
You're a bad judge of character
and your shirt looks like vomit.
So we can go see
North by Northwest.
We are not seeing
a movie together.
Good call. Smart.
Keep it profesh.
Hey, Captain.
So, you found something?
Hey, I like the tie.
If you can't beat 'em, join 'em.
Anyway, I think I got
something good here.
Turns out the name
Ratko is made up.
But I was digging
through these files,
one of which I literally
found in a spider web,
and it turns out there were a bunch
of references to a Serbian thug.
Street names, "The Rat"
and "The Butcher."
He was known to hang out at a
storage unit near Boerum Park,
which has red soil, hence,
the muddy red footprint
on Morgenthau's counter.
That's fine work, Detective.
Thank you very much, sir.
A testament to what can be achieved
when you dress appropriately.
Let's pound it out.
You know what?
Such fine police work.
Let's share it
with the whole team.
Santiago, Boyle,
Diaz, get in here.
Bring everyone.
And a camera.
That's not necessary.
Let's have a hand for the work
of the fine... Oh, they're here!
...master detective,
Jake Peralta.
Yeah. Let's have a hand,
everyone. Give him a hand.
Yeah, nice!
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Looking good!
No record of Ratko
on the ledger.
Must have used cash.
Well, I for one am just pumped to
be on a stakeout with you, Captain.
You know what my favorite
thing about stakeouts is?
Patrol Guide says no dress code.
So I'm just
the zip-up hoodie
and my two best friends.
Does he always talk this much?
I just tune it out.
It's like a white noise machine.
Okay, first of all,
that's racist.
Secondly...
Captain, Terry told me you
caught the Disco Strangler?
I mean, that's incredible.
I've read that case.
With all due respect, sir,
why'd it take you so long
to get your first command?
Because I'm gay.
Uh...
Seriously?
I'm surprised you didn't know.
I don't try to hide it.
Did anyone else get
a little bit of a gay vibe?
Manscaping.
Damn.
I am not a good detective.
Here. I feel bad
that you spent all that
money on the movie tickets.
Why don't you just go to
the movies with me? No.
Okay.
Well, this is awkward.
It's not awkward.
I like your company.
You're sweet.
When did you come out?
About 25 years ago.
The NYPD was not ready
for an openly gay detective.
But then the old guard died out,
and suddenly, they couldn't
wait to show off the fact
that they had a highly
ranking gay officer.
I made Captain,
but they put me
in a public affairs unit.
I was a good soldier.
I helped recruitment.
But all I ever really wanted
was my own command.
And now, I finally got it.
And I'm not gonna screw it up.
Uh, Captain, I'm sorry. I...
I feel like a jackass.
But, on the flipside,
there's Ratko.
Humility over.
I'm amazing.
Fantastic.
3,000 identical blue doors.
Looks like we all got door duty.
Oh, yeah.
From before.
Good one.
You look great.
Clear.
Okay.
Unbelievable.
Unbelievable!
Ratko, great to see you.
You can't stop me.
I'm going.
Actually...
You're not going anywhere.
'Cause if you take a look to your left
you'll see Detectives Boyle and Diaz.
Right there
is Detective Santiago.
And behind you is Captain Holt.
Point is, my team
has you surrounded.
Oh, my God! I just
got the tie thing!
Captain, I just figured it out.
Maybe now's not
the best time, Detective.
It's a uniform.
We're a team, and the tie is a part
of that team's uniform, right?
You ask Ratko what team?
No, Ratko, shut up.
It's important to you, because you
were kept off the team for so long,
and now you're the coach
and you want us to all
wear that same uniform.
Boom! Nailed it.
Yes, you did.
Now, just arrest Ratko.
All right, Ratko, down.
Drop the weapon.
Hands on your head.
Here we go.
He's running!
Go!
Got him.
Hands behind your back.
Hands behind your back!
Stay down.
That's how we do
it in the Nine-Nine, sir.
We catch bad guys,
and look good doing it.
What's wrong with you?
Never took off the Speedo.
Big mistake.
It is inside me.
Great work, team!