- My fellow detectives,
ours is not an easy job.
The hours are long.
The danger is constant.
The pay is LOL.
But today, a glimmer of hope.
For today...
a new vending machine.
[applause]
Behold him
in all of his glory.
So full of strength
and promise,
and most importantly,
sodium, gluten, and fat.
- Whoo!
- The time has finally come
to christen the machine.
Boyle, the champagne?
- Oh, well, technically
it's a Hungarian Pezsgo
from the Tarnok Valley.
- For once in your life,
don't ruin it.
Give him the bottle.
- Thank you.
I hereby christen thee
Snacky Chan!
[electricity crackling]
Whoa!
Okay, well, at least it
was just the keypad.
None of the snacks
got messed up.
Whoa!
Go!
- Oh, right!
- Okay, okay.
[fire alarm beeping]
- No!
It should've been me.
It should've been me!
[upbeat music]
ReEncoded By Dr.XJ | PSA
www.PSArips.com
[foghorn blaring]
- Our perp's name is Karl Ove.
My CI said he's selling
counterfeit caviar
out of a blue stall.
- This place smells
like a squid farted
inside a whale's butt.
- [sniffs]
Yes, that is the exact combo
of smells.
Nicely done.
Hey, next week is my
six-month anniversary with Amy.
Should I do something special?
- You know what I like about
our relationship, Jake?
We don't talk about
our love lives,
or our families, or anything
that's on our minds.
It's why you're
my closest friend in the world.
- Yeah, I know,
but I need help on this.
I asked Boyle
and he was useless.
- Put a baby in her, Jake.
What are you waiting for?
- So do that then.
Problem solved.
Look, it's our guy.
- Excuse me, sir,
we're with the NYPD.
I just need to ask
you a couple of--
Oh, shrimp!
I hate that!
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- [grunts]
- You're under arrest, punk.
Nobody gets away
from Jake Per--ew!
Something yucky touched me!
Ugh, gross,
gross, gross!
- Hang on.
What's that?
- What have we here?
- [speaking Swedish]
- What?
- I have no idea
what you're saying.
[speaking Swedish]
Just as I suspected
immediately.
- It's a flawless
39-carat diamond
that was stolen
six weeks ago
from the Royal Stockholm Museum.
- I've just received word
from Interpol
that two detectives
are on their way from Sweden
to pick up the suspect.
Please make them
feel welcome.
- Welcome?
We're gonna roll out
the fricking red carpet.
Working a jewel heist
with Interpol?
This is the best thing
that's ever happened to me!
Second best.
- Aww.
- [whispers]
First best.
I was lying to Amy.
- [sighing loudly]
Do you guys know anyone
who wants some used textbooks?
- I'd love them.
It's never too late to teach
yourself something new--
- So no one.
Great.
- Why are you
throwing those out?
- Because I'm
never gonna pass
this astronomy final,
so I won't graduate,
so my life is ruined.
- Or we could
help you study.
I did graduate
magna cum laude from Syracuse.
I know that sounds
like a brag.
And it was!
Terry killed it in college.
- Plus, I know a thing
or two about astronomy.
I had 11 straight birthdays
at the planetarium.
That was also a brag.
- My God, you guys are
such pathetic nerds.
But maybe that's what
I need right now,
pathetic nerds.
Okay.
You pathetic nerds
can help me.
- Thank you?
- You are so welcome.
- Peralta, Diaz.
This is
Inspector Knausgaard
and Deputy Inspector Carlsson.
Their flight here
was eight hours.
It's been a pleasure
talking with you
about the duration
of your flight.
Good day.
- Well, there goes
my opening question
about how long
your flight was.
- It was eight hours.
- Yeah, no,
I got that.
I was joking, sorry.
It must have got lost
in translation.
- No, we understand
you perfectly.
Everyone in Sweden
speaks English.
- We also speak Norwegian,
Dutch, German,
French, Russian,
and Finnish.
But not Danish.
That is a garbage language
for garbage people.
- Yeah.
- Oh, word up.
Well, I have almost
memorized "Gangnam Style"
phonetically, so samesies.
- I don't know this word.
"Samesies"?
- From context, I believe it
means "proudly uneducated."
- Ah.
- So...
- No.
- Where's our prisoner?
- Being processed.
But, in the meantime,
may I offer you some
of the finest cuisine
in Brooklyn from my
favorite restaurant?
The food cart outside
the precinct.
It's really good.
- Hm, none for Soren.
He's allergic to lactose,
gluten, and tomato ketchup.
- Oh.
- Also, none for Agneta.
She and her husband
are trying
to have another baby,
so she can't
eat anything
that will alter
her cervical pH.
- Oh.
- You guys are
real close, huh?
- In Sweden, we believe
for a proper team to function,
partners must be completely open
with each other.
- Yeah.
We have no secrets.
Not even our bodies.
We sauna together
all the time.
- Yeah, well,
we are also very close.
One time, Rosa saw me
in my bathing suit.
- No, I didn't, you told
me to turn around.
- Yeah.
- Well, uh, since we cannot eat
your disgusting street food,
could you please check if our
prisoner has been processed?
- Yeah, we don't mean
to offend, it's just
this place is filthy and you
both seem unprofessional.
- Unprofessional?
Well, we were going
to take you to our favorite
laser tag place, but now,
you're officially uninvited.
Rosa.
- Ah, Boyle. Just the man
we were looking for.
Kevin has accepted
a fellowship to teach
at the Sorbonne
for the next six months.
- Oh, I love Paris.
At least how
it's represented
in the movie
"Ratatouille."
- Uh...
- The rodent chef.
- Ah, yes.
Farfetched.
- Anyway, Kevin and I belong
to the Park Slope Racquet Club,
where we've established
a squash doubles dynasty.
- We've taken home the trophy
two years in a row.
Unfortunately, I'll be flying
to Paris this year
during the tournament.
It's a seven-hour flight.
- [whistles]
- I remember you told me
you played in college.
- Three-time intramural
champion at Sarah Lawrence.
Would have been four, but
senior year I played Greaseball
in our school's production
of "Starlight Express."
- Interesting casting.
In any case, I would be honored
if you would take my place
so that Raymond
could make it a treble.
- Absolutely!
I would love to do that!
- Great.
- Formidable.
- Yup!
That is great.
This is great.
This is terrible.
- Why?
You always said you wanted
more face time with Holt.
- No, not like this.
Squash brings out
my competitive side.
breaking racquets, cursing,
excessive mooning.
One time, just to
psych a guy out,
I locked eyes with him
and ate a squash ball.
- That's not possible.
- It's still in me, Terry.
- Look, the point
is to have fun.
So just relax
and have fun.
- Right, right,
right, yeah.
It's just a game.
It's fun.
There's no need
for Holt to see me
unleash the beast.
[laughs]
Okay.
- That's a strange
little man.
- Probably telling Captain Holt
how much they like
to sauna together.
- Please.
They think they're so great
just 'cause
they know
each other's allergies.
You know
what I'm allergic to?
- Yup. Them.
- Totally.
And also bees.
You should know that.
If I got stung by a bee,
I could die.
- Detectives, I've been talking
with the inspectors.
There's been a development
in the Kottbullediamant case.
- Excellent pronunciation,
Captain.
- Tack.
They believe our perp
may have smuggled more
stolen Swedish diamonds
into Brooklyn.
- Oh, well,
thank you for the tip.
Have a wonderful flight home.
We will send you the jewels
as soon as we find them.
- They're staying and
working the case with you.
- Ah, fantastic.
Rosa, could you please fill
my car with a million bees?
- Okay, since the Swedes
are rudely late,
let's talk
anniversary gift.
Should I get Amy something
caszh like shot glasses,
or something less caszh,
like golden shot glasses?
- Still don't care.
How about I get a jump
on our new partners
and search the perp's apartment?
- Right. We'll get some
clues, solve the case,
make them look like fools.
They can eat our
American dust.
- No, no.
Soren is probably
allergic to dust.
- Oh, hello!
Yes, I am allergic
to dust.
- Everyone is.
That's what sneezes are.
- You're what sneezes are.
- Okay.
[clears throat]
What are you guys
doing here?
- Oh, in Sweden,
we call it police work.
Perhaps you don't
have a word for it?
- [whispers] I hate you.
- This is our case.
You can't work it
without us.
Get your weird,
hairless fingers off of it.
- Soren shaves his fingers
for cycling.
It cuts down on drag.
- Agneta is my
biggest fanatic.
Just as I am a fanatic
of her slam poetry.
Would you like to hear some?
- Would I like to?
I would hate to!
- Your loss.
Well, we've already searched
the entire apartment.
- Yeah, well,
now we're gonna search it,
and find things you all missed,
like this!
- Your own keys?
- Damn straight.
Bag 'em, Diaz.
[keys thud]
- Astronomy is full
of interesting facts.
For instance,
here's one that
Hollywood doesn't
want you to know.
A parsec is actually
a measure of distance.
One of the many inaccuracies
in the "Star Wars" universe.
- Uh-huh.
And what's "Star Wars"?
- Oh, boy.
Maybe I'm getting ahead
of myself.
Okay, let's talk planets.
Jupiter is a gas giant.
- So is Hitchcock.
How does this help me?
- It also has 67 moons.
I came up with
a fun mnemonic device
to remember them all.
It goes,
"Every Individual Gets Crayons
"After Telling His Aggressive
"Little Mongoose Painter
Called Ernest
"Some Lies About
Tiny Panda Heads--period--
"Maybe One Kid Could Take
Her Elephant
Into California, Except--"
Where's Gina?
- She told me you called me
a gas giant.
Well, now you and I
will never hook up.
- Uh-oh.
What's this?
A little piece of evidence
that evaded
your bald little hands.
A shipping manifest
that was shoved
into the back
of a drawer.
- Our perp transferred
a container
to a shipyard in Bay Ridge
on October 11th.
- That arrived
over a month ago,
I doubt you'll find
anything in it.
- Please,
you're just pissed
we cracked the case wide open
and you've got nada.
That's right,
I speak Spanish.
- Actually, we've got
much more than nada.
- Damn it,
he speaks Spanish too.
- Agneta found an invitation
to a party tonight
at the home of...
Alvar Gustavsson.
- The hot blond guy
from "True Blood"?
- No, the Swedish
millionaire
with ties
to organized crime.
Alvar Gustavsson.
- Yeah.
- Oh, that...
Alvar Gooz-hev-vren.
Well, you're welcome to
pursue that dead-end lead
while we got to the shipping
container and find the jewels.
And maybe to celebrate,
Rosa will wear them
to your dumbass party.
- No, they're priceless,
please do not do that.
- Yeah, obviously
we wouldn't.
We were just being jerks.
See you later, jerks.
- Okay.
- Bye, Jake. Bye, Rosie.
- Whoo!
You ready, Boyle?
Psyched up?
- No, why?
Do I seem psyched?
'Cause I'm
definitely not.
I just want to have fun.
- And to win.
- Hey, if we all have fun
and don't throw any racquets
and don't eat squash balls,
then we're all winners.
- What?
- Nothing. I'll serve.
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
- Out.
- What?
Are you out of your mind?
That was...
fun.
That was a fun call.
You're a real
fun guy, fun guy.
This is fun!
- Gina!
I know astronomy can seem
a little daunting
and scientific,
but I have a friend
who I think
can make it
pretty interesting.
- Who dis?
- Hi, Gina,
I'm Neil deGrasse Tyson.
- And I care, why?
- Director of
the Hayden Planetarium.
One of the world's
leading astrophysicists.
And he's doing me
a huge favor.
- And how do you know
Terrance, Space Tie?
- We're gym buddies.
- [grunting]
Damn, Neil deGrasse Tyson!
How are you doing that?
- It's physics, Terry.
It's physics.
Gina, look.
Give me two hours.
You'll not only
pass your exam,
you'll gain a deeper
appreciation of the universe
through which we journey
on this spaceship Earth.
- Spaceship Earth?
Way to go.
You just made Earth lame,
and that is my house.
- Gina, why did you want
to take astronomy?
- Because I thought
it would be cool,
just me, sitting around
naming moons left and right,
like "Zorp," "Bong,"
"Dingo."
"Etcetera," that would
be one of the names.
"Etcetera."
- She's gonna fail,
isn't she?
- Big time.
- Yeah.
- According to
the shipping company,
the container that came in
on October 11th is 34G1.
- Cool.
Hey, what did you
and Marcus do
for your
six-month anniversary?
Keeping in mind, that he's
dreamy and romantic
and I only own $50.
- Marcus and I broke up.
- What? When?
- A month ago.
- A month ago?
How do I not know
about this?
- Because we don't
talk about that crap.
We're not lame
like the Swedes.
- Right.
Yeah, totally.
If Agneta broke up with her
husband, she'd probably be all,
"Oh, Soren,
I am so heartbroken,"
and he'd be like,
"What can I do to help?
I'm sorry,"
and give her a big old hug
and she'd be all
feeling better
like an idiot.
- We don't need
to do that
because what we do together
is solve crimes.
- You know it.
For example...
34G1.
Boom.
We are about to uncover
a butt-load of diamonds.
- Exactly.
- It's fish!
It's fish, Rosa!
- Ugh.
[indistinct chatter]
- Swedes.
- Oh, hello, Jake.
You missed quite a party.
The blond man from
"True Blood" was there.
Very cool guy.
- So cool.
- Yeah, that's cool.
Hey, this is weird
because I hate you guys,
but can I ask you a question?
If you broke up
with your husband,
would you tell Soren
about it?
- Are you making a funny
laugh joke right now?
I would insist
he be there for it
so that my husband would
have a shoulder to cry on.
- Yeah, several years ago,
Agneta and Lars
were having trouble conceiving.
She didn't even have to ask me
to donate my sperm.
I had it already in a
"Tooperware," ready to go.
- Wow, that's...
so gross, yeah.
- Can we ask you
a question?
- Mm-hm.
- Why do you smell like fish?
Is it hygiene?
- No, we spent the night
cutting open
hundreds of dogfish to see
if they had diamonds inside.
- Did they?
- Wouldn't you like to know?
- Yeah. It would be pertinent
to the case.
- They didn't.
Although, one did have
a battery in it.
What kind of a sicko feeds
a battery to a fish?
- Well, while you
were wasting your time,
we set up a meeting
on 14 November
with the man we think
is the buyer.
- Um...
- No, don't worry, Soren.
I rescheduled your cycling
practice for 16 November,
and your dentist
for 19 November.
- You know me so well.
- [giggles]
- Ugh.
Those guys suck.
They're so into each other,
they're probably
gonna start holding hands.
Oh, they're actually
holding hands.
- Yeah, they are awful,
for sure.
All tall and beautiful,
and you don't
want to know what they've got
in their "Tooperware."
But honestly,
I don't know that it's
that bad that they're close.
- Wrong, it's the worst.
- Okay.
- Oh, my God, I just figured out
where the diamonds are.
We thought the shipping
container came in
on October 11th,
10/11, but dumb Europeans
write their dates backwards.
We should've been going through
the one from 10 November.
- Of course!
Stupid rest of the world,
writing their date all dumb.
- Yeah. Let's go.
- Okay.
- Boyle.
Is everything okay, you know,
with your brain?
- Yeah.
I'm great.
I'm having a lot of fun.
- Yes, I've heard you
say that 162 times.
You do realize, that if
we lose this next match,
we're out of the tournament?
- Yes, but the important thing
is we had a good time.
- No! The important thing
is that we win the trophy.
Because I promised Kevin
before he left
for Paris that we would do that.
Do you know why
I chose you as my partner?
- Because I'm the most
athletic person you know?
- No, because of an article
I read
in the
"Sarah Lawrence Phoenix"
about a young man
they called
"squash's unhinged lunatic."
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
- According to that article,
that lunatic was 27-0.
I need him on my team.
I need you
to unleash the beast.
["Wild Side" by Motley Crue]
- ♪ Take a ride
on the wild side ♪
- Whoo!
You butternuts ready
to get squashed?
"Huh? What? Duh?"
That's you guys
while I smoke your butts,
because Ray-Ray and the Beast
don't even give a what.
We don't give a what.
Unh-uh.
Whoo!
Let's do this.
♪ ♪
Boo-ya-kah, suckers!
[both grunting]
- ♪ Wild side ♪
- Yeah!
- Ohh!
What?
You kidding me?
Are you kidding me?
- [grunts]
- Yes!
Whoo! [slaps]
- Ow!
- Way to go!
That's it, baby!
- Gina, great news.
- Oh, no.
Is Neil deGrasse Tyson here?
He will not stop trying
to friend me.
- No, but we think
we figured out how
you're gonna pass your test.
- Yeah, we realized that
we were trying to get you
to learn using our methods.
- We should've been speaking
your language.
[dance music plays]
The language of...
both: Dance!
- 13.8 billion years ago,
there was nothing.
- And then the big bang!
- Yes!
Now, Amy, back up till
you feel the wall.
And, Terry, ditch the shirt.
I'm ready to learn.
♪ ♪
[both panting]
- And that's how you calculate
parallax distance.
- So you ready
for the test?
- Oh, I took it
this morning.
I passed.
- What?
- It was nice how much
you guys cared,
so I actually opened up
my textbook for the first time.
Ya'll, astronomy is
kind of interesting.
And I am hella smart.
- Then why'd you make us
do that whole dance?
- Two reasons:
Uno and dos.
- I get that.
- One-two, one-two,
one-two, one-two.
- Ha-ha!
I guess we are
the better team.
Why do people like
these things?
They're just shiny rocks.
- Yeah, totally.
- You should be happier.
We found the jewels,
we won.
- Yeah, you're right.
We should celebrate.
Why don't we go to a bar
and drink in silence?
- Cool.
Sounds good.
- No, I was being a bitch.
How did you not
pick up on that?
- What is your problem,
man?
Is this about your stupid
anniversary present?
- Yeah, that, and you
not telling me about Marcus.
We're supposed to be friends.
- You sound like
Soren or Agneta,
whichever the boy one is.
- Well, say what
you want about them,
but at least they communicate,
you know?
I've never even heard
your slam poetry, Rosa.
- Why do you
all of a sudden care about
every single little detail
of my life?
- Because all we talk about
is cop stuff.
All right, and that was fine
when we were 20
because that's all
I cared about.
But we're adults now
and there are other things,
like me and Amy
and you and Marcus,
that friends are
supposed to talk about.
- Well, I guess
we're not friends then.
- [scoffs]
Wow.
All right,
I guess we're not.
[truck rumbling]
Oh, uh-oh.
- We're moving.
- Oh, really?
Thank you for sharing that
intimate detail about your life.
- Jake.
- I know, we're screwed.
I was being a bitch again!
- All right,
I called for backup.
I also texted
all of my friends.
You'll notice your phone
didn't buzz.
- I think we're in Red Hook.
We're not on the BQE anymore.
- Nice try, Rosa.
Don't try to kiss up
to me by mentioning
my third-favorite
New York expressway.
- Shut up!
We pulled into
a parking lot.
Things are about
to go down.
- Backup won't make it here
in time.
It's just me and you.
- I heard two voices
in the truck.
There'll be more
if there's a meet-up.
- Go word is "Glurg."
- Copy that.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Flergen!
Come on, is that you?
I haven't seen you
since Blorgenbergen, man!
- Who the hell are you?
- Give me a hand,
you old dummy.
It's me, Glurg.
- NYPD!
Drop it!
Drop it, you're under arrest.
- I hope they have saunas
in Swedish prison.
- They do, actually.
They're quite nice.
- Oh.
- Kevin, there's something
we'd like to show you.
- Ta-da!
- Ah, magnifique.
The treble is ours.
I look forward to getting
number four next year.
- Actually,
we've been banned for life
from all future tournaments.
- Oh, no.
What happened?
- My fault, Kevin.
I snapped the second-place
trophy over my knee
and threw it in a urinal.
- Oh, my.
- Yeah.
- But the important
thing is,
we had fun.
- Yeah.
- So we'll be taking the jewels
back to Sweden tomorrow.
- Yeah. Guess you were
wrong about us, huh?
Bet you feel
pretty stupid.
- Actually,
when you're wrong,
that means you've
learned something.
And any opportunity
for learning is good.
- Ugh.
You are the absolute worst.
I hope you die
in a fjord.
- No, no, we are
trying to say we are happy
to have worked with you.
- Yeah, I know.
That is an infuriating attitude.
- Yeah, I second
the fjord thing.
- [speaking Swedish]
- Bye, Jake.
Bye, Rosie.
- It's just how they
walk around, I guess.
- Get your hands
off each other, weirdos.
- God.
- Well...
[sighs]
Nice job today.
I guess we didn't have
to know each other
to have each other's backs.
So drink in silence?
- This sucks.
We solved the case and told
the Swedes how to die.
I should be happy,
but I can tell you're bummed,
and that's not cool
'cause we are friends.
- Really?
- Yes.
And I thought of what
you should do
with Amy for your anniversary.
- Oh, thank God.
I got her a boogie board.
It has an iguana
playing electric guitar on it.
She's gonna hate it.
- New York Public Library
lets VIPs stay there overnight.
- Ooh, that's perfect.
But wait, how do I become
a library VIP?
I forgot to return "Superfudge"
in the fourth grade,
and I've been scared
to go back ever since.
- Don't worry about it.
I can hook you up.
My new boyfriend works there.
- [gasps]
You shared!
What's his name?
No, wait.
I don't want to push too hard.
- No, it's cool.
I want to tell you his name.
- Oh, okay, just gonna
take a quick drink break.
Here comes the name.
Nope.
Uno mas.
All righty.
Good Lord.
Putting them away.
I have to imagine these belong
to someone else.
- It's fine.
- Yeah.
- It's Tom.
- [gasps] I love it!
- Not a doctor.
Shh.