Nazeem Khan, you made a statement
at a party in London
that you're not married
but you do have kids.
-That means you're in a live-in.
-You've disgraced the institution
of marriage and Indian culture!
What are you guys saying?
I celebrate festivals like Eid
and Diwali.
After doing marriage oriented movies
how can you say such things
about marriage?
Says who? Who said I abused?
You need a controversy, right?
You'll never get it.
Is this a publicity stunt for a movie?
And even your late night parties
are always in news.
It's my life.
I can do whatever I want.
Whether I party till late in the night
or have a live-in...
how does it matter to you?
Live-in, huh...
So you being termed
as anti-national is right.
Tell us. Please tell us.
He's gone.
-Nazeem Khan.
-Down-Down.
-Glory to...
-Culture Protection Party.
Radhe-Radhe!
There are quite a few similarities
between a politician and an actor.
They are both drama queens...
and they both want publicity.
And lots of it.
No one knows what Nazeem Khan said
but it certainly deemed
love a sin in UP and MP.
Suddenly live-in relationships
had become a national issue.
Nazeem Khan's movie posters
were torn down...
Lovebirds faced the brunt of it too.
Because according to
the Culture Protection Party...
any kind of a pre-marital relation
is against Indian culture.
They have their own set of rules.
And in case you don't like their rules...
you are free to raise your voice.
Feel free to raise your voice.
It won't change anything but
you may end up having a sore throat.
With cameraman Abbas Shaikh,
I am Guddu Shukla for Mathura Live.
-Nazeem Khan.
-Down-Down.
Beat him!
HIDE AND SEEK
The protest over Nazeem Khan's statement
has taken a violent turn
in many parts of North India.
You can see how the workers
of Culture Protection Party
are apprehending young lovers
and blackening their faces.
As a result colleges remained closed
in various parts of the city.
But the biggest question
that still lingers is...
"Is this really
a question of culture
or just a PR stunt
for the upcoming elections?"
We'll find out after the break
from Culture Protection party's ex-MP
from Mathura, Vishnu Trivedi--
Guddu, I spoke to the people
from Diamond News in Delhi.
They want us to do another job
before the Gwalior Elections.
They want us to prepare a report
on opinions of different people
on marriage and live-in relationship.
They will telecast it
as an interesting feature.
We're ready, sir.
Just tell us when to begin.
-Hello, Mr. Trivedi.
-Come, Uncle.
Come sit. Come, Rashmi.
-Mr. Pandey.
-Hello, sir.
-How are you?
-All is well.
It's okay...
Come, sit. Get some tea.
What can I order for you, Mr. Trivedi?
There's no need for this formality.
Tell me how's your channel doing.
Well, thanks to you, it's doing good.
How's your political party doing?
The Culture Protection Party.
Well, it's doing better than ever.
And I owe it to these traitors...
who disrespect
our country, our culture and religion.
We're protesting against Nazeem Khan.
We won't let any of
his movies to be released in UP.
If we spot his picture at any salon
we'll burn it down to ashes.
The picture, the shop
and even the cars parked outside the shop.
-Long live revolution--
-Okay...
Mr. Pandey, she's my daughter Rashmi.
Hello.
-I told you about her over the phone.
-Yes...
She returned from Delhi a week ago...
after getting a degree in Media studies.
She also did her schooling there.
My younger brother lives there.
Uncle runs a transport
business in Gurgaon.
He owns 72 trucks. How many?
Seventy-two...
And none of his trucks
ever stops at the toll...
Rashmi was saying that
she wants to go back to Delhi...
to work as an assistant in a TV channel.
That's internship, Father.
Exactly.
But I said my friend Pandey
owns a channel.
It's right here in Mathura,
you can do your internship here.
This way she can stay
with us for a few more days.
-Mr. Trivedi, this is your company.
-See...
-Rashmi.
-Yes.
I must tell you one thing
before you start working.
We're not a big news channel.
We run a cable-news channel.
And also do some freelance work
for the news channels in Delhi.
I don't have a problem.
And anyway, it's just for a month.
I am not planning on staying here forever.
So this way I'll get to
know the local news network...
and I can put this on my CV as well. So...
Fine. You can join us tomorrow.
We were just discussing a report.
You can join in if you want.
-Yes, of course.
-Great.
Let me introduce you to our team.
This is Guddu Shukla, our star reporter.
Only a fool wouldn't know him.
He's the face of your channel.
A one-take artiste.
I've seen you reporting on TV.
Your style's quite different.
Thank you.
Elections are around the corner.
And I am contesting
the parliamentary elections again.
I'll give you a couple
of interviews as well.
Uncle...
Interview him too.
And that's our cameraman.
-Yes.
-Abbas.
-Radhe-Radhe!
-Walekumsalam.
Radhe-Radhe!
So we're with the sage from KC Ghat.
So, sir, this new issue on
the block about live-in relationships...
where the boy and girl live
together without getting married...
what is your opinion on it?
Look, son, ever since I was born...
I've only worshipped Radha-Krishna.
From whatever knowledge of the scriptures
I possess, I can tell you
that they were not married either.
And there is no better love story
in this world, than theirs.
So you mean to say that live-in
relationships are not wrong.
As long as there is love,
everything's chaste, dear.
Without love, it's wrong to
look at anyone with such intentions.
"All the books in the world won't
show you the path to enlightenment.
But those who experience love,
get enlightened."
I have a question, Guddu.
If Shah Jahan had a live-in
relationship with Mumtaz...
would he have built the Taj Mahal?
Taj Mahal is not the symbol
of Shah Jahan's wedding...
it's the symbol of his love.
Don't you have any better things to do?
Why are you bothering me
for this nonsense!
Where the hell have you come from?
You...
Live-in is a good thing.
I was in a live-in
for eight years in Delhi.
But there are other issues
in the country that you can cover.
Many issues. So cover them.
This is a stupid issue.
-You're in a live-in?
-What's wrong?
-Leave my hand.
But is live-in our culture?
Live-in is just an excuse for sex.
Just find me a girl
and I'll take care of the rest.
Right?
Living with a girl without marrying her?
I hadn't seen my wife's face
before marrying her.
I just did what my father said.
And now I am the father of three.
I wasn't floored
by your handsome face either.
All thanks to your government job
and your father.
Otherwise
you would've still been a bachelor.
God save us from such a wife.
She is very dangerous.
Hello, ma'am. We're from TV news.
Why are you yelling?
I am old, not deaf.
We wanted to ask you some questions.
Go ahead and ask whatever you want to.
-Would you like to ask her instead?
-What?
Would you?
-Okay.
-I see...
She is going to ask her.
-All the best.
-Thank you.
Am I looking fine?
Wait a second. This profile is better.
-Looking better from this side.
-Ma'am, right?
-Ready, Rashmi? Camera rolling.
-Yes.
Grandma, a new system has taken
the country by storm these days...
where the boy and girl
live together before getting married...
in order to know each other.
In the same house.
So what is your opinion on it?
That's a really nice system, dear.
If, before my marriage, I had any idea
that my husband was a drunkard...
I would never have married him.
The rascal died in his youth.
he left me with neither children
nor respect.
-Thank you.
-Listen...
Take my advice.
Don't ever marry a guy until
you know him well.
-Rashmi, let's go.
-No, I won't.
Yes, she won't.
-Leave her.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Don't you forget that.
-Sure.
-Rashmi, let's go.
-I won't.
Very good, ma'am.
-Everybody says "She rocks".
-She rocks!
Ma'am, bye!
By the way, Guddu...
what is your opinion on
live-in relationships and marriage?
My opinion?
Even I feel that if there's love,
everything is chaste.
But if there's true love,
why hesitate to get married?
If tying a knot gives the respect
to your relationship in the society
then isn't it better to get married?
-Are you married?
-No.
-Any girlfriend?
-None.
Okay.
-Why?
-Just a casual question?
-Do you have a BF?
-BF?
Not anymore.
So you did have one?
Just a casual question.
I did, back in college.
-And then?
-Then what? I shot back to reality.
Meaning?
I mean people act so stupid
when they're in love.
They don't see what they should.
Sometimes they get impressed
by someone's branded clothes...
and sometimes by the perfume they wear.
And you face reality
when the perfume fades.
-So you're single.
-What?
I mean... I don't need a perfume at all.
I smell good naturally.
Really?
You have a bad taste.
Bye!
I see your photo
Many times in a day
If you've got the footage you needed,
shall we leave?
Many times in a day
There's a storm raging in my heart
You come in my dreams
And give me sleepless nights
Come meet me once
I see your photo
Many times in a day
If you know about his parents or owner...
then please contact Mathura Live.
This is Guddu Shukla,
reporting from the lanes of Mathura.
You've driven me crazy
I can't live without you
Nor tell you what's in my heart
You've driven me crazy
I can't live without you
Nor tell you what's in my heart
You're my dawn
And my beautiful night
The world seems wrong
And you're the right one for me
Be my love
Listen to your lover
Be generous to me
I see your photo
Many times in a day
There's a storm raging in my heart
And?
That's all.
What's the matter?
You're going pretty fast today, Shukla.
Your life is on the fast track now.
Chuck it.
You're out of your mind. I am
riding fast because the road's empty.
I see...
And what about that wide smile
you've been wearing all day?
Did you prop up your
lips with a hanger all night?
It's all because of love, my friend.
While looking for new stories,
you've started your love story.
Tell me, what if her father finds out?
When in love, there's no place for fear.
Love is never planned. It just happens.
Pretty amazing.
I will pray to God...
that your love story becomes
immortal like that of Radha-Krishna.
What happened?
You do know that Radha and Krishna
never got married.
These things were okay
during Radha-Krishna's time.
But this is a different age now.
This is Mr. Vishnu's age.
And, son, Krishna was a god...
and you're an ordinary man
who couldn't even clear college.
Uncle, we caught him in the bathroom
with a girl.
Disgusting.
People go there to relieve their bowels
and you were romancing there.
What do we do with him now?
What else?
Give him a proper bath.
I'll blacken your face and
take you around the city on a donkey.
Elections are around the corner.
Blackening his face will do no good.
Let's shave his head then.
Why are you hell-bent on performing
Mr. Yadav's final rites...
while he's still alive?
Then what else do we do?
How many children does Mr. Yadav have?
He's got four other sons,
not counting this one.
Good.
Even if one of his
sons becomes a cripple...
the other four can
carry the lineage forward.
Great. Let's go.
Killed me
Bollywood, Hip-Hop, Salsa, Moonwalk
Sunwalk, Kanjivaram, Kuchipudi...
festival dance, wedding dance, political
dance, we teach all of the above.
What do you want to learn?
Dance?
I came here to see the plot.
Plot? We have that too.
1BHK, 2BHK, bungalow plot, tower.
And, mister, nothing can beat a bungalow.
Judging by his face, I think
we'll have to show him the cheap ones.
We'll give you a good
deal on an expensive...
I'll give this man a good deal
on an expensive plot.
Show him the pictures,
I'll be right back.
Give me the new one.
What's your salary?
This is a new print in chiffon.
It will look stunning on you.
This is another color.
-This?
-Even green will look nice on you.
How much for this one?
This one and this one for 350 rupees.
350 rupees?
-This one?
-Yes.
But it's available in
the market for 100 rupees.
What are you saying, madam?
That's too little.
Why don't you quote your price?
Rs. 55!
Rs. 55?
Yes, Rs. 55 is good.
Take it for free.
That hanky outside costs 55 rupees.
There's a limit to haggling.
Fine. I'll pay Rs. 65.
Forget it, ma'am.
-Why?
-Leave it.
You can pay Rs. 100.
This price is only for you.
-Pack it.
-Have you lost it?
Never... I won't sell you this sari
for anything less than Rs. 300.
Strange.
You two are quoting such different prices.
Done.
-I'll pay Rs. 100.
-Never.
-Rs. 300...
-Wait, Vikas.
Jasmine?
Chandni.
Jasmine.
Myself Babulal.
But people call me Chand.
Who on earth talks to you
or calls you Chand?
Madam, nothing less than 300 rupees.
Take it or leave it.
The deal's done in 100 rupees.
Here are your 100 rupees.
-But how...
-Hey, no arguments.
We can't sell you this sari
for anything less than Rs. 300.
Father...
She'll pay 100 and
I'll pay the remaining 200.
Pay up.
First, pay. Pay up.
Please leave,
we don't want to sell this sari.
Why not?
I said pay him the 200 rupees.
Stop winking at me.
You think you own this shop.
Bloody rascal.
Who do you think you're abusing?
Yes, this is your father's shop.
Then why don't you handle the business?
Both your brothers sit here
dressed as females all day...
bloody ordinary reporter.
You are going to tell me what to do.
Bloody mutt...
-Control him.
-Stop him.
Don't call me that.
I have a reputation here.
You have developed this area,
haven't you?
Guddu, why do you argue
with him every day? Let him go.
He's my brother-in-law.
Brother, he's a disgrace
to all brothers-in-law.
He comes here to ogle at women.
Guddu, let him go!
And go home.
-Brother-in-law, I may do something.
-What will you do?
Guddu.
-Leave him.
-What are you doing?
I didn't do anything
because you are
my brother-in-law's brother.
But things have gone overboard now.
And yet you're still alive.
I won't die so easily.
But you can burn.
Run fast.
Shall I burn you?
-Brother-in-law!
-Leave me.
Shall I burn you?
Your sister-in-law will kill me.
Mr. Dubey, you want to say
-that they didn't like Vikas, right?
-Yes.
But they also said that
they have no objection
in getting their daughter
married to Guddu.
What nonsense!
When we're trying to
find a bride for Vikas
then how does Guddu
get involved in all this?
Which picture did you send them?
Why didn't you dye your hair?
I did, Mother.
But I wrote my actual date of birth.
Mr. Shukla, you won't find such a family.
Why don't you ask Guddu once?
He may agree to marry her.
Go on. Let someone get married,
Father-in-law.
At least I'll have a person
to help me out with the chores.
I can't do all these chores alone now.
I'm tired of washing their loin cloths.
Brother-in-law, give your consent.
He's not getting married anytime soon.
What nonsense.
And who wears loin cloths in this house?
-I see...
-That's enough.
And you, Mr. Dubey. Why do
you bring such stupid proposals?
Why don't you ever
bring a decent proposal?
How many more proposals
do you expect me to get?
Do you have any idea how many proposals I
sought for you over the last 8 years?
Right.
And the very first proposal
was of my daughter's.
She got married and has three kids now.
I am afraid these two
might remain bachelors forever
and Cheeku gets married first.
Mom, even I want to get married.
Shut up, Cheeku.
He wants to get married.
Do you even know what marriage is?
Even you're unmarried, how do you know?
Cheeku, quiet.
Don't yell at the kid.
He is talking about getting married.
These days people are living
together without getting married.
-Like that Nazeem Khan.
-Dubey!
Don't you dare talk about him!
You won't utter his name.
The celebrities these days.
This is what they are
teaching this generation.
I can't stop thinking
about his parents' ordeal.
It's better not to have children
than to have someone like him.
-Fine. Calm down. Calm down.
-Bravo. Bravo.
Don't spoil your health
for that shameless man.
Mr. Dubey, you tell us what to do next.
They are looking for someone
with a high-profile job.
Mr. Dubey, no job's too big or small.
Great.
Then why don't you handle
the sari business?
Has the doctor advised you to come on TV?
Why are you interfering?
Father, please tell him
to keep his mouth shut
-or else I will kick him out some day...
-Just a minute.
Dubey, there's no room for debate on this.
I said I don't approve of
this proposal then that's final.
Go and tell them that.
Fine.
But there's one thing
that's still unclear to me.
The younger brother is getting
married before the elder one. How?
Who's getting him married?
Whoever gets married first,
what is your problem?
What do you mean by that?
Look at that, Father.
I think his intentions are evil.
Babulal is right about you.
Who are you guys to
form an opinion on me?
And I'll get married whenever I want.
I'll get married before you if I want to.
-You'll do it first!
-Who's older amongst us?
-Vikas--
-I am older.
So I will get married first.
And if you get married before me,
I'll beat you to pulp.
Now you just watch.
I was just contemplating this idea
but now I've decided.
Brother. Book a wedding venue.
Now I will get married first.
Vikas, remember what I had said.
He will get married before you.
And if that happens,
the society will look down upon you.
Cheeku.
-You rascal...
-Listen...
No one would want to
let their daughter marry you.
-They'll say that your system's rusted.
-Is your system working good?
Why don't you yell out
louder and let everyone know?
Why is he shouting?
Father, you be quiet.
Take my advice, Guddu, and get married.
I am afraid these two
might remain bachelors forever
and Cheeku gets married first.
Cheeku's uncle, bless him.
A suit in this weather?
Were you attending a wedding?
Wedding... Yes... I mean no.
You're looking nice.
So what was so important?
Hello, Brother.
What on earth are you doing?
Brother?
-I came to propose to you.
-Marriage?
Are you out of your mind?
What is this charade?
This is not a charade, just my feelings.
You do love me, don't you?
Yes, Guddu. But love and
marriage are two different things.
I am not ready to get married yet.
I mean... I still have to go to Delhi,
get a job, become a journalist.
And I am not stopping you from doing
any of this.
But you can do all this after marriage.
And we'll settle down
in Delhi, post wedding.
Even my career will take off in Delhi.
But I don't know you so well, Guddu.
How can I marry you on such short notice?
I am not telling you
to get married right now.
But marry only me.
Whether we do it now or later,
we must get to know each other better.
And we can never do that
if we keep meeting secretly.
What else do you want to know?
I am like an open book.
And one needs time
to read an open book. So...
Remember what that old lady said?
If she had any idea that her
husband is a drunkard
she would never have married him.
But I don't drink at all
and you know that.
It's not about alcohol.
Then what is it?
Sit down. Sit.
Look, Guddu,
I've already made this mistake once.
And I don't want to do it again.
So until we don't spend
some quality time together...
Let's do this.
We should go for a live-in.
-What?
I'm saying that we should
go for a live-in first.
How can you bring that topic up?
Technically it comes before the wedding.
We should give it a try too. Everyone is.
Everybody in Delhi and Mumbai do it.
The population of Delhi and Mumbai
is over 20 million, Rashmi.
Perhaps it's easy to do it there.
And we're in Mathura, it's a small city.
We can't walk hand-in-hand,
how do you expect us to go for a live-in?
Moreover Nazeem Khan has created
quite a stir in the city.
Even brothers and sisters can't step out
of their home because of your father.
And you want to go for a live-in with me.
Why are you such a wimp?
It's a matter of a few days.
Let's try staying together for a few days.
If everything goes well,
I can give marriage a thought. Yeah!
I don't get it.
Despite being a girl, I'm not afraid of
a live-in, why are you so scared?
Gender is not the problem, Rashmi.
I am a well-known person in Mathura.
Even the dogs and cats
of this city know me.
Your father is pretty well acquainted too.
Here we're always on our toes
so that no one recognizes us.
I don't understand how
we will go for a live-in.
And when? What will we tell our family?
And the most important question
where are we going to stay?
-Gwalior.
What Gwalior?
We are going to Gwalior
to cover the Municipal Elections.
It's a 20-day job.
And we'll request Mr. Pandey
to send Rashmi with us too. That's it.
You mean to say that we should
go to Gwalior for 20 days.
Do our job and also try
our hand at a live-in relationship?
-Absolutely.
-That's great.
What an idea, Abbas. You're brilliant.
That I am.
This is the best idea you can get.
Away from your family.
Tell them it's an official trip.
And get what you want.
Why? What are you thinking now?
What is the problem now?
It's far away from home.
And no one knows you out there.
So no one will know
and we can do what we intend to.
Done.
Done. Done.
You two look cute together.
Father, whatever you taught me
Whatever I have gained from you
I'll take to my groom's home
I'll take it to my groom's home
With fond memories
I go to a strange house
Your dearest
Uncle!
How will I manage to forget, Father
The stories that you have told me?
I'm going to leave behind
All the memories of childhood...
-Did you check the hotels?
-No, I'll do it now.
Why stay in a hotel?
Why go for a live-in
if you're going to stay at a hotel?
Is it written in the scriptures
that during a live-in,
we can't stay in a hotel?
Unbelievable.
Tell me, when does
a boy and a girl stay at a hotel?
-When?
-That's what I am asking.
When does a young girl and a young boy
stay at a hotel for 15-20 days?
-On their honeymoon.
-Honeymoon.
That's the right answer.
And when does one go on a honeymoon?
-After the wedding.
And when does one go for a live-in?
Before the wedding.
Exactly. Then why do you need a hotel?
And anyway, living in a hotel is not
considered a live-in relationship.
When a boy and a girl stay
in the same house as husband and wife
without getting married,
that's called a live-in relationship.
Simple.
Are you an expert on this subject?
How does it matter whether
we live in a hotel or a house?
It does matter. Abbas is absolutely right.
As long as we don't live in
the same house as husband and wife
-we'll never get to know each other.
-Yes.
And everything is available
in the hotel on demand.
The staff cleans the room for you.
Food's available on a phone call.
And they even do the laundry.
Girls are intelligent.
Other than this,
there's only one thing left to do.
For which, you'll need a bed.
If that's on your mind,
you can book a hotel.
No, we're not going to do that.
What do you mean?
Means?
I mean we'll do everything
that a husband and wife normally do.
So?
Well, a husband and wife do that as well.
Don't get too excited
and keep your eyes on the road.
Think of a way to get a house in Gwalior.
I didn't hear anything.
O my beloved
What was the name of the hero
who featured in that song?
-Nazeem Khan.
-Yeah, Nazeem Khan.
Even you two are in a similar situation.
Great.
-But there's a problem.
-What is it?
Have you heard about
the Culture Protection Party?
What about them?
They created quite a stir after that news.
Their party workers are a bunch of dogs.
-What are they?
-Dogs?
You mean we can't get a room anywhere.
At least not in Gwalior.
Where are you going?
I said it's difficult but possible.
-Sit.
-Meaning?
I mean, only I know
that you two are not married.
And I am not going to tell this to anyone.
And if you don't tell anyone either
then no one will know.
Secret.
What is marriage?
Wear a nuptial chain
and vermilion on your forehead.
And you are married.
No one's going to ask you for
your marriage certificate. Right?
And even if someone does,
we'll arrange for that too.
Everything's available here.
One can get a death certificate
for a man who's still alive.
I got one for my uncle when he fell sick.
-Property matters are a real hassle.
-I don't mind.
All it takes is a little vermilion
and a nuptial chain.
-That's all.
-I am ready.
-Yes.
So what now? Shall we proceed?
Come on.
Come, sir. Come.
Here's your little love nest.
For an entire month.
It has got everything you need.
And the best part is
that the owner lives abroad.
He comes here only once in a year.
He came down here last month
and will be back next year.
But this one's Indian.
Exactly, madam, Indian.
Everything in here is Indian.
East or West, India is the best. Tell me?
How is the water facility?
24/7, ma'am. In fact,
even the rainwater seeps directly in.
We're not going to stay that long.
And what about the neighbors?
I hope they won't create problems.
No problems at all. I am here.
So we've to pay you
Rs. 6000 for this place?
What?
-Rs. 10,000.
-But you just said Rs. 6000.
That rate is for a married couple.
And you're going to stay
here without a license
so it's going to cost you extra.
What do you mean without a licence?
Meaning without getting married.
Marriage is the licence
to do anything you want.
Since you're going to do
things without getting married
you'll have to pay the fine.
Just like you do if you
drive a car without a licence.
Yes, we get it. Pay him.
Here you go.
This is for keeping your mouth shut,
for the days to come.
-Keep it.
-Thank you.
Now you won't face any problems.
I guarantee you that.
Hello. Hello...
Myself Soni Shrivastav.
I live in the house no. 12.
Are you guys the new tenants?
Yes.
He's Mr. Guddu.
And that's his wife Rashmi.
And he's Abbas.
-Hello!
-Hello.
So when are you guys moving in?
-Well, we just did.
-Okay.
And it's a lucky day. Tuesday.
It is a very auspicious day.
I watch Ramanand Baba's predictions
on television every day.
Actually... I see all the programs on TV.
Why don't you install
cable TV in your home too?
I'll give you their number.
Yeah...
In today's age,
you can do without a husband
-but not without a cable TV.
-Yes.
Well, then see you in the evening.
Right, Rashmi?
Yeah, see you in the evening.
-Thank you.
-Thank God!
Just a minute.
I forgot to ask where you are from.
-Allahabad.
-Benaras.
She's from Allahabad.
He's from Benaras.
And he's from Kanpur.
And I am from Gwalior.
Right? Here's my card.
Okay.
Bye.
Bye, dear.
Grapes, mango, strawberry...
The shower doesn't work.
It's there as a showpiece.
I had to use the bucket instead.
Back in Delhi, every house had a shower.
Are you going to say something?
I am speaking to you.
I am listening.
What did you hear?
It's a nice home, isn't it?
Very nice.
Come on, now let's sleep.
So soon? It's just 1 a.m.
It's 1 a.m. Now sleep.
Are you asleep?
No. Why?
I can't sleep.
Wake up.
And what do you expect me to do, Guddu?
I read an article on live-in
relationships, on Google.
It was a really nice article.
It explained what to do
how to do and in which way.
Just like Abbas said.
Live-in is about living
together like a husband and wife.
Understood?
Are you asleep?
Guddu.
I am very tired.
Actually, do we have protection?
We do. Lots of it
and in different varieties too.
You're cute.
-I'd eaten a lot of butter in childhood.
-Really.
Guddu, careful.
I am the only guy from Shukla family
who's getting this experience
before getting married.
How does one open this damn thing?
-You know... Google's...
-Yes.
...really amazing.
One should always follow what it says.
I want to do it again.
Do it.
I am not getting that.
Who has come?
Hello, son. Good morning.
Good morning, ma'am.
-Where is your wife?
-Which one?
Which one? How many wives do you have?
I am talking about Rashmi.
-My wife Rashmi?
-Yes.
She's still asleep.
Anything urgent?
No, I just wanted to say that if
you need anything feel free to ask.
Yes, of course.
-Bye, son.
-Bye.
What a peculiar woman.
The one who can't live without cable TV?
Yeah. She's always
snooping around our house.
That's too much water,
it's completely dissolved.
I can't eat this.
You'll have to eat whatever we have.
This is all we'll get in Gwalior.
Mr. Gwalior, I'll handle the cooking,
no need to worry.
You take care of the washing,
cleaning, dishes, etcetera.
I should do all the work
and you only cook for two people.
You know what, you handle the cooking,
cleaning and dishes.
And I'll do the rest.
Okay. But you'll clean
the toilet and bathroom.
You clean the toilet
and I'll clean the bathroom.
Come on, Guddu, that's the least
you can do. It doesn't take that long.
And I'll handle the cooking,
you got to do all the chopping.
-That's not my cup of tea.
-I am not chopping anything, Rashmi.
I am not asking, I am telling you.
Now make me a nice cup of tea.
And I don't like ginger, so
don't forget to add cardamoms.
Lots of cardamoms, huh?
I'll show you.
Run...
My heart calls out to you
Let's build our own little world
I can't stand any distance between us
Just you and me, and no one else
Everything that's mine is yours too
You can keep my share of happiness too
I take your name with every breath
And my heart beats for you
We're building 15 temples
all over Gwalior.
Now you can ask God for anything you want.
Roads, electricity, water.
Anything you want.
You'll get everything you wish for.
But only when you have faith.
What an amazing ideology of
the Culture Protection Party.
They are such uncomplicated people.
I can't get enough of you
Nothing affects me now
You're my love, my life
And my world
All I can think of is you
Without you
A moment seems like forever
My heart calls out to you
Let's build our own little world
If you're ever sad, I'll make you laugh
You can keep my share of happiness
I take your name with every breath
And my heart beats for you
Sister, you have this
knack of snooping around.
I don't believe you.
Sometimes she wears the nuptial chain,
sometimes she doesn't.
Sometimes I see the anointment
on her forehead, sometimes I don't.
I am sure she does
but you must have missed it.
I am telling you.
I saw them and heard everything.
They were dividing
the chores amongst them.
They were running around
in the house like little children.
In their underpants.
We've been married for so many years.
But my husband never chased me,
in his underpants.
Right?
My husband wears a lungi.
Doesn't he wear underpants?
Mrs. Kohli, you've very naive.
I learnt to laugh
Only after I met you
I learnt to live my life
I've forgotten the world
Ever since I met you
You're my heart, my love
I can't stop talking about you
My heart calls out to you
Let's build our own little world
If you're ever sad, I'll make you laugh
You can keep my share of happiness
I take your name with every breath
And I breathe as your heart beats
The path of love brought me this far
Finally I understood
The meaning of love
Never leave me, sweetheart
I'll be lost
Hello, dear. How are you?
Hello, ma'am.
Sorry for troubling you at this hour.
-But my husband's in the mood...
-What?
-For a cup of tea, dear.
-Okay.
Can I borrow some milk?
Yes, of course. Come in.
-Come in.
-Okay.
-Hello, ma'am.
-Hello, son.
Thank you.
So, son, how's work?
-Work?
-Yes.
It's amazing.
Great.
For how long have you two been married?
-1 year
-6 months.
-6 months
-1 year.
Great.
See you then.
Bye-bye, dear.
-Mrs. Kohli.
-Yes.
Listen, Mrs. Kohli.
What's wrong?
Didn't I tell you, Mrs. Kohli?
I caught those two red-handed today.
Yes.
They have no clue how
long they've been married for.
Now it's confirmed that they
are in a live-in relationship.
And it's all that Nazeem Khan's fault.
People like him are
a blot on our society.
-Yes. And on our neighborhood too.
-Yes.
Mr. Kohli, now you must throw
those two out at the crack of dawn.
-We're dead.
-Yes, we're dead.
What now?
We should've already decided
on how long we were married.
You should've thought about it, Guddu.
And why can't you
ever give the same reply?
If dad finds out about this,
he'll bury you alive.
-Respectable people live here.
-Right.
-Decent people live here.
-We must throw them out.
-We can't allow them here.
-Such people can't live here.
-I wonder how they came here!
-Throw them out.
Come. Let's see.
Knock the door.
-Call them out.
-Decent people...
You? And with all these people?
-Please come in.
-Move aside.
Come inside everyone and see for yourself.
Hello.
They are married.
Yes.
They...
They are married.
I swear this wasn't here.
And this was definitely not here. Really.
I swear on Ramanand Baba. Honestly.
He is lying.
They are looking so cute here.
Listen, dear.
Wow! You people have come
on a very nice day.
Nice day?
You see, it is our
first wedding anniversary.
-Have sweets.
-Congratulations.
Congratulations...
-But she said...
-Have a sweet, ma'am.
Let's go.
After all,
it's an auspicious day for us. Smile.
-We just breezed through these 20 days.
-Right?
These were the most
beautiful 20 days of my life.
Mine too.
I'm getting a very
strong feeling about this.
Then what's the next step?
Next step?
What's that?
Well, for starters,
it can be what we came here for.
We'll see.
-Let's go.
-What's wrong?
Nothing.
Something's definitely wrong. What is it?
I did all this for you.
And you're still uncertain.
I love you a lot, Rashmi.
I've no clue how much
Lord Krishna loved Radha.
But I can bet you that
I don't love you any less.
I've imagined my entire life with you.
And we look really happy.
But there's one thing
that always scares me.
What if you refuse to marry me?
Why do you think that I'll refuse?
I don't know.
What if the perfume fades away?
Even if it does, you smell nice naturally.
I am not in the mood to joke, Rashmi.
Have you ever been to Jaipur?
It's the best place
for a destination wedding.
-Is it?
-Jaipur.
-Jaipur!
-Yes.
People are watching. Control yourself.
How can I control myself?
I can hear the wedding bells.
Can't you ever slow down?
We leave for Mathura tomorrow.
Then talk to our parents.
And then you can imagine
all the wedding bells you want.
-Happy?
-Yes.
You came to Gwalior with me.
But you're always
busy staring at other girls.
-I am looking at the guy.
-Why?
Are you interested in guys as well?
No. Hold this.
She's a married woman.
Even I am married.
Or have you forgotten that?
No.
Who is he?
Forget him, Bobby.
Fooling around with a married woman.
But I won't let you
have all the fun alone.
I want it too.
What do you want?
Go back to the hotel.
I'll see you in an hour.
Make that two.
Shall we go?
Nice tires.
-Happy Holi, ma'am.
-Holi?
Hi.
Mad man.
I'll get that.
Yes?
Tell Guddu I am here. And I want some too.
What do you want?
The same that Guddu...
Yes?
What do you want?
Do you want a towel?
Are you okay?
What do you want?
-Who was it, Rashmi?
-It was some weird guy.
He said he wants something
and was talking about you. He just fled.
He talked about me and fled?
There's only one such man.
And he's in Mathura.
Welcome to Radio City 91.1 FM!
I bring you fresh songs...
Keep listening to Radio City 91.1 FM.
In love, there's no place for fear
It's just love and not a sin
So why cry over it?
In love, there's no place for fear
Guddu, come out fast.
When in love, no need to be afraid
So why cry over it?
In love, there's no place for fear
It's just love and not a sin
So why cry over it?
We are doomed.
Vikas, remember what I said?
Your younger brother
will get married before you.
Now look.
Now you'll have to spend
the rest of your life alone.
Didn't you feel ashamed
before doing any of this?
Did you ever think what will happen to me?
You rascal. Stop look at her. Look at me.
You wanted to get married, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Couldn't you have waited for a few days?
Even I was getting some proposals.
Vikas! What is going on here?
Get out.
What is this?
You should know
that no one in Shukla family
has ever done such a thing.
The younger brother
got married before the elder one.
Nobody eloped and got married.
But you wanted to change
the course of history, didn't you?
Which you did.
Are you happy now?
Why did you do such a thing?
Why did you elope and get married?
Such a nice girl.
I admit that she's underdressed.
We would've let you marry her.
You could've asked us once.
At least you could've told me once.
Look, Mom, strawberry.
Cheeku.
Guddu, shameless.
How can you leave this thing lying around?
I didn't expect this from you.
Imagine our reputation in the society now.
Forget your reputation.
Think about poor Vikas.
His life's ruined now.
He'll die a bachelor now.
Very sad.
-Whatever happened wasn't fair.
-Get lost!
There's no way brother Vikas
can face anyone now.
You bloody...
Will you both shut up?
This is our personal matter.
So please don't interfere.
Stop yelling at my brother.
What's done, is done.
Now we need to ask her whether she
can handle the household chores or not.
Be quiet, Sister-in-law. Be quiet!
And why can't he speak?
What family? Which family?
A family where the younger brother
has no respect for his elder brother.
Thankfully, Babulal informed us on time.
Or else he was planning
on eloping with her.
Look. His bag's packed.
How did this happen?
Where to, Mr. Khan? You were
the only one missing in the picture.
Please. Didn't you bring your
camera along?
Abbas.
So you knew all about this.
I am asking you a question. Did you know?
-Yes.
-There you go.
Everyone knows except for our family.
Stop staring at her.
We know the entire story.
We're just missing your version.
At least you could've told us.
Or at least stopped them
from doing such a thing.
What could I possibly say?
All I can say is that
forget what happened.
And forgive them.
And get these two married.
Marriage.
Have you lost it?
How can we get them married again?
Are you on drugs or something?
You mean they won't get married?
Have you lost it?
When they are already married
-then why get them married again?
-Right.
Married?
When?
Oh yes, they are already married. Look.
See this picture, this frame.
They took their wedding vows
in my presence.
But unfortunately, none of you were there.
I mean get them married again.
For the sake of the society.
They just need your blessings.
Yes, do that.
This is right.
We just need your blessings, Mother.
Yes, ma'am, no wedding is complete
without the blessings of the parents.
Will you two shut up?
You didn't tell us anything
about your parents.
Who are they?
-Yes.
-Yes?
Who?
That...
I had warned you about this.
But my fear turned out to be true.
What on earth have you done, Rashmi?
Didn't you think about
your father's reputation?
Elections are around the corner.
We'll become a laughing stock
of the city.
And you said, "Shrikant, I'll be
the next MP, the next minister, the CM."
Now when they expel you from the party,
all your dreams will be shattered.
I am feeling dizzy.
Everything's over now, Uncle.
Dear, what have you done?
-What have you done?
-Aunt is crying.
You could've told us once.
He's such a nice boy, such a nice family.
You should've tried telling us once.
We would've let you marry him.
-I've something to say.
-Here comes the bad luck.
I know none of this is right.
But nothing is over yet.
For your sake and for the sake of society
you should get them married again.
What say?
-What is he saying?
-Best idea.
-Come closer.
-Yes.
In our culture,
marriage is a one-time affair.
And they are already married, got it?
But, Uncle, how are we going
to explain any of this to the people?
Like when did they get married?
Why didn't we inform anyone?
We've been promoting
our culture for ages now...
but your very own daughter
just put all your efforts to waste.
I'm telling you, we've been cursed
by all the lovers that we humiliated.
The highest leader of Culture Protection
Party, Vishnu Prasad Trivedi's daughter...
eloped and got married.
This is going to create a stir.
There will be no such thing.
Keep your mouth shut.
I know how to tell the people about this.
They eloped and got married.
Well, at least they are married.
And not in a live-in relationship
like that rascal Nazeem Khan.
-Yes.
Sir?
What if we were in a live-in relationship?
You are telling this in front of uncle.
I will clobber you.
What is he saying?
Then a number of bodies would
be floating in the Yamuna River.
-Count them.
-They are six.
Their bodies.
Understood?
-Shrikant.
-Yes, uncle.
Come here.
I don't want to see that guy again.
-Understood?
-Yes, Uncle.
Hey...
No, I'm not talking to you.
We're in conversation with the ex-MP
of Mathura Mr. Vishnu Trivedi.
Let's begin our conversation with him.
It's a very happy day for him
because it's the wedding
of his only daughter Rashmi.
It's done...
-They just got married.
-They did?
Yes.
So, Mr. Vishnu, my question to you is
how do you feel after this wedding?
It feels really nice.
It feels really very nice.
My dear daughter is married
to a very talented young man Bunnu--
Guddu Shukla.
...with Guddu Shukla.
We received many
proposals for our daughter.
From rich families.
Many proposals.
But I wanted my daughter
to marry someone from a poor family.
Yes. Right.
They are very poor people.
But as you know that I don't
believe in caste, creed or community.
But the boy's from a Brahmin family.
And they have a huge
sari shop in Mathura Market.
Pardon my insolence
but I do have a question, sir.
Yes, of course.
It's your only daughter's wedding.
Why didn't you invite anyone?
Because it was my father,
Late Dwarkadas Trivedi's last wish.
That his granddaughter's wedding
-be a private affair.
-Right.
A personal affair, understood?
Why did he have such a weird last wish?
We don't know.
Why don't you ask him personally? Shall I?
No... I get it.
Ask him.
-Priest.
-Yes.
The groom's here, so is the bride,
the garlands and the guests.
So shall we take our wedding vows?
Go ahead.
But who's going chant the hymns?
Why, sir, can't you?
I only look like a priest
but I am not one.
I sell fritters outside.
Mr. Shrikant called me in a hurry and said
I should walk out
with you two when he calls.
The wedding's done.
-Hey, fake priest, get them here.
-Yes...
You both are married now.
Seek blessings of your parents.
Come on hurry up.
You're the bride and groom,
so show that you're happy.
This is not a funeral. Smile.
Come on, fast.
Our Rashmi's husband and
our brother-in-law is here.
Now everything will be okay.
Gentlemen, they are married now.
Now you can come and bless
the couple in any way you wish.
-Congratulations...
-Congratulations.
Hello.
Come on, that's all.
Come on smile now.
Come on, that's it. Let's go...
Come on.
Cry. It's your send off. Cry.
She was like my daughter.
Uncle, shed some tears.
My dear daughter...
Please take care of her.
Cry...
Seek their blessings.
Father-in-law.
Take care of our daughter.
Bless you, dear.
Don't cry. Don't cry. Let's go.
Uncle!
Bye.
Please stop her.
Be quiet.
Please stop her, Uncle.
Come, Aunt. Let get some tea.
We are made for each other
I am always with you
Your love has floored me
I'm a beauty like
The mountains of Chamba
Your image dwells in my dreamy eyes
My feet look bare
Whenever you go to the town
I won't ask you for much
Bring me an anklet, Oh, beloved
My feet look bare
Whenever you go to the town
I won't ask you for much
Bring me an anklet, Oh, beloved
The one that's sold on the streets
Your image dwells in my dreamy eyes
Come here.
Careful.
Go... Go...
Tell us in the morning.
Ankita, it's your turn.
Ankita, don't cheat. Are your eyes closed?
-Pappu, Rani, Pinki... Let's go.
-One, two, three, four...
You were amazing yesterday, dear.
So were you, Mother-in-law.
Are you guys ready?
-You're back early today, son?
-I am coming.
Yes, Mom. It was a lazy day at work.
Rashmi, why didn't you go with him?
You should go to work too.
What's wrong with you, dear?
I've been noticing that you stay pretty
reserved ever since you got here.
-If any of it is our fault, then--
-Not at all. Please don't say that.
I am absolutely fine.
Guddu, is something wrong?
No, Mom. Why do you think so?
We got married in such haste,
so she is just tired.
Yes.
And our house is so congested
which she's not used to.
Okay.
But, son, whatever happened,
I am happy with it.
Actually, even I couldn't have
found such a beautiful bride for Guddu.
Right?
She's one in a million.
Don't be sad, dear.
Let's forget what happened.
You two are newly married so
learn to enjoy these moments.
These moments will never come back.
And once you have kids
then you'll hardly get
the opportunity to be a wife again.
Did I say something wrong?
-Not at all, I--
-No, she...
-She can't cook.
-Cooking problem.
Yes.
Silly girl.
Women are not made
only for cooking and cleaning.
And why do you have to cook?
You're from such a nice
family and educated as well.
You should go out. Anyone can cook, dear.
Absolutely right, ma'am.
In fact, she's much
more educated than him.
-Really?
-Yes.
In fact, she should go
to work and Guddu should cook.
Right?
Yes. At least we'll get some good food.
So it's decided.
Guddu will cook
and daughter-in-law will go to work.
-Done.
-Fine.
-And we'll sit at home and eat.
-Right.
Come on. Give it to me.
You people, sit here.
I'll finish my chores.
-Janki.
-Yes!
Here you go.
Frankly speaking, it's hard to find
a mother-in-law like her these days.
-Rashmi is very lucky, isn't she?
-I can't do this.
What are we doing?
Your parents have accepted me so easily.
They treat me like a daughter.
And what am I doing?
I've been deceiving them.
This charade...
I never imagined that the weight
of this lie would get unbearable.
I am so full of guilt.
Technically, we're
still in a live-in relationship.
This will be the first live-in where
the whole family is living together.
This is not right.
Do something, Guddu, please.
We had decided to get married
when we get back here anyway.
So let's get married somewhere secretly.
And no one will know.
I cannot live the rest
of my life like this.
Please do something.
Abbas, listen.
Remember the temple on the hill
-the one where we'd reported of weeping
sounds being heard every night.
-Yes.
-Go there tomorrow.
Give the priest 1100 rupees and tell him
that two people will be
coming there to get married.
He'll make all the arrangements.
But he recognizes you.
Don't worry.
Just tell him a different name.
Okay.
One happy family.
Get off.
What? Don't look at me.
-Cheeku.
-Yes, Uncle.
-What are you doing here?
-I am hiding here.
We're playing hide and seek.
Hide and seek?
Did you hear our conversation?
-I did, I heard everything.
-What?
We were just joking, dear.
Aunt, I might be a kid
but I'm not stupid.
I understood everything,
that you two aren't married
and you people are making
a fool of everyone.
And you're going to get married secretly.
Isn't that right, Uncle?
Uncle, I was playing hide and seek
but you got caught red handed.
Okay, come.
Let go.
-Cheeku, whose is that?
-It's mine.
Uncle Guddu bought it for me.
His wedding gift.
Looks expensive.
-It's worth Rs. 8000, Grandpa.
- Rs. 8000?
Why did you have to
buy such an expensive one?
You should've bought something cheaper.
It's all right.
He's just a kid.
And he wanted a cycle from a long time
so I thought of buying it for him.
But he never wanted a cycle.
He wanted a video game.
The one worth 500 rupees.
Isn't, Cheeku?
I'll get that too pretty soon, Grandpa.
The one worth Rs. 2500, right, Uncle?
Oh, God! Why on earth
did you bring me here?
Why? What happened?
Those guys belong to my father's
political party. They know me.
-Oh, God! Cover your face.
-Yes. Okay.
-And don't take it off.
-Okay.
-Wait a minute.
-Yes.
If they are your party workers,
I am sure they recognize me too.
I am your father's son-in-law after all.
Even your parents won't
recognize you in this stupid beard.
What will happen if they see me?
Couldn't you find a different temple?
Couldn't you find a different father?
His henchmen are always lurking around.
There are more than
4000 temples in Vrindavan.
Did you expect me to
check all of them overnight?
You could've checked this one temple.
Fine, let's go.
Let's go.
Where is he?
Priest.
Rahul and Damayanti?
-No. Ranveer and Damayanti.
-No!
Damayanti.
You're Ranveer and I'm Damayanti!
Sit...
Priest.
Now grace her forehead
with this vermilion.
She is already married. Look at her.
She's already married.
You've made me commit a sin,
you bloody rascal.
Calm down, Priest. That was a mistake.
-She isn't married.
-Yes.
Ashok... Rajan...
What's the matter, Priest?
Look what he's making me do!
He made me commit blasphemy by
getting him married to a married woman.
-I am off to take a dip in the river.
-Rascal. What's your name?
-Ranveer...
-Ranveer or Shahid.
-Listen to me, Mister.
-Listen, Mister, I am not married.
We were just practicing.
Listen, lady, religion is
not something you can toy with.
You should be ashamed!
You're lucky that we don't abuse women.
Now please leave.
Come on.
Mister, I wasn't trying
to insult the Hindu religion.
Nor the culture of our country.
I love my country and my religion.
There is no other culture
in this world like ours.
Where golden birds perch on each
And every branch
That's my beloved India!
Long live India!
Brother Vikas, get a good
green colored Benarasi sari
-from your shop and hang yourself.
-Why?
Guddu's getting married again
while you're still a bachelor.
I can't get married once
and he's getting married every week.
-Where is he?
Here I am, Brother.
Rascal, didn't you feel ashamed?
I never imagined you'll
turn out to be such a rascal.
Who was that lady?
And how did you grow a beard overnight?
Looking at his actions,
he's got to hide his face.
The elder brother's still unmarried
and the younger one's
walking down the aisle again.
He was trying to marry a married woman.
-A married woman?
-With a married woman?
-Let's go.
A married woman is someone's wife,
someone's pride and honor.
He was going to ruin someone's life.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Why are you doing this? Why?
Look, first, you got married secretly.
But we didn't say anything.
And now you're getting married again.
What's wrong with you, Guddu?
-What is all this, son?
-What is all this?
What is all this? I don't get it!
-Speak up or else...
-No! No!
Are you out of your mind?
Grandma, I'll settle for
that 500 rupees video game.
Hey! Don't interfere.
Honestly, I pity that poor child.
I am worried about her.
I am telling you.
If her father finds out about
his antics, he will kill us.
The end.
-Mother. Father.
-Look at her.
How much more are you
going to make us suffer?
He won't learn his lesson like this.
No...
I apologize, Brother. It was a mistake.
I ate something on the way and now
I am not in my senses.
Just one request.
You can scold me all you want
but at home.
Don't create a scene here.
The veneration will start
and people will gather.
-Take me home. Please take me home.
-Let's go. Come on, let's go.
-Come on. Let's take him home.
-We'll beat him once we get home.
I'll not spare you.
-Let's go home.
-You shut up...
Quiet.
-Let's go, Vikas.
-Leave me.
-We'll beat him.
-Wear your slippers.
Hail the Lord!
Why didn't Guddu come?
He's at home,
busy with some important work.
And I am jobless, right?
No...
Don't stand there like a watchman.
-Sit down.
-Yes.
I was speaking with Rashmi over the phone.
She sounded very depressed.
And sad.
I hope there are no issues.
No...
Did the couple have a fight?
I don't pay you to sit around.
Water the plants. They are drying.
Look, sir, I want to make
one thing pretty clear.
My daughter is my happiness,
she's my world.
Yes, that's true.
And her happiness is your son Guddu.
If Guddu doesn't keep
my daughter happy...
I will be very sad.
And there's no way you can survive
in Mathura after making me unhappy.
Understood?
Look. You're a Brahmin and so am I.
You're nothing when compared to my status.
So for everyone's sake,
the next time when I meet Rashmi
she should look happy.
And not like you.
Understood?
-Shrikant!
-Yes, Uncle. Coming.
-Yes.
-Will you have tea?
-Get some tea for him.
-Yes.
Add more sugar to it.
To maintain the sweetness
in our relationship.
Don't leave without having tea. You too.
Okay.
Shrikant is a rascal.
He put eight spoons of sugar in the tea.
I feel my mouth's covered in sugar.
This is an insult,
we are the groom's family.
Look what he's looking at!
Look, son.
I know that men of your age
do have some needs.
They get bored being served
the same thing over and over again.
And often they want a change in
their palate with different varieties.
And one also feels that there's
no fun in life if there's no variety.
We do understand.
But it's important to
keep your desire under control.
Who's called an ideal person?
Someone who controls his capricious heart
and lays the foundation
of a happy married life.
And he's the one who commands
respect in the society.
While the rest have no place.
Do you understand?
I don't understand
what you're trying to say.
We're the ones who don't
understand what's going on.
Kamla, go inside.
Why have you been behaving
so lustfully these days?
Were you bitten by a monkey?
-Lustful?
-Yes.
Monkey?
I am not bitten by any monkey.
Nor are my desires out of control, Dad.
How do I tell you what's
going on in my heart?
I want to tell the truth to everyone.
But then Mathura will be on fire.
You'll be in total shock and that
Trivedi will die of a heart attack.
Lustful!
-What's he saying?
-What's going on in his mind?
You're so stupid. This is all your fault.
Couldn't you remove the vermilion and
nuptial chain before going to the temple?
If I wear the vermilion,
there is a problem.
If I don't, that's still a problem.
Do you think I am used to this?
And you gave us all these ideas.
You sent us to Gwalior
and also arranged the temple.
I see.
You wanted a live-in relationship
and you wanted to get married.
I was just helping
you guys out as a friend.
-Otherwise why would I care?
-I see, so it's all my fault?
Shut up, you two. It's all my fault.
Happy now?
My family has stopped talking to me
because they think
I am some lustful pervert
who is trying to marry someone else.
And is cheating on you.
And father told me how
your father threatened him
saying that his daughter
should always look happy.
Do I torture you every night?
Why can't you smile while talking
to your father over the phone?
I am not crazy to keep smiling
all day without any reason.
And your family reaches wherever we go,
like a mobile network.
If her father has threatened your father,
then what is her fault in this?
Shut up.
It was you who said that
we shouldn't stay in a hotel.
Hotels are for after wedding.
This would've never happened
if we were put up in a hotel.
I see. So it's all my fault now?
Stop it, you two.
Let's forget what happened
and think about what to do next.
How do we get married, Guddu?
Always Guddu...
Guddu doesn't know.
In fact, Guddu is so desperate
that he can get married
right here if someone's willing
to recite the wedding hymns.
Actually, I've run out of mobile data.
Can I get the Wi-Fi password?
Abbas, we don't have Wi-Fi.
See you then.
By the way, I've another plan.
Look.
And nothing will go wrong this time.
I swear on God.
I wonder what's wrong with Guddu.
She's a lovely girl
and I don't know what he is up to.
Come.
No, dear. You don't have to. Let it be.
Go and rest.
This is not your job.
No, Mother-in-law, I'll do it.
So, dear, all okay?
Yes?
Mother-in-law, can Guddu and I
visit our family deity's temple.
Yes, of course. Go ahead.
Just... take care of him.
If you take proper care of him at night
you won't have to worry about him
at other times.
-She is right, you know.
-Yes.
Men are like a money plant.
They need constant watering as well as
direction.
Otherwise they go out of control.
Keep him entertained.
In fact, give him something
to look forward to every night.
And he'll never look
at any other woman again.
Every night he'll come
home like an eager beaver.
Where are you going?
To the temple.
Temple?
Again?
No, we're going to Rashmi's
family deity's temple which is close-by.
Deity? Who is their family deity?
He must be having a name.
God is known by many names.
But He's still God after all.
Shall we? Father-in-law?
Go on, dear. Come back soon.
Okay.
And, Rashmi, hold his hand.
Had there been familiarity
Living would've been easy
-Ravan!
-Lord Ram!
Ravan!
-No, Sri Ram.
-Where is Lord Hanuman?
-Ravan!
-Brother, they are running away.
-How did he get here?
-How do I know?
They are running. Run faster.
Had there been familiarity
Living would've been easy
Don't let go of
The person who stole your heart
What's your name
Had there been familiarity
Living would've been easy
Aunt.
This man has gone astray again.
They are running. Catch them.
They are running. Hurry up.
Had there been familiarity
Living would've been easy
The night is young and may it not be lost
It won't be coming back on anybody's call
Wait a second.
Why are we running?
What?
I mean they don't know anything.
Then why are we running from them?
Yes.
Why are we running from them?
Wait, you rascals.
Brother, they are coming towards us. Run.
You made me run in this sari.
Why are we running?
I don't know.
I am running because you're running.
Shut up. Stop.
-What?
-What? That's what we want to know.
Why are you following us?
We're worried for you, Daughter-in-law.
You don't know that your
husband is characterless.
This rascal was trying
to marry a married woman.
You were marrying someone else?
Rashmi, he's talking
about the temple incident.
Yes, that's fine.
Don't you have a problem if
your husband marries someone else?
Chotu, where does one find such girls?
Stop worrying about me.
Why were you following us?
You left home after making an excuse
of your family deity.
So?
So what?
So, you'll know whether we're
actually going to the temple
-or not only when you follow us.
-Yes.
Then why are you following us?
I wasn't following you, I was on my way.
To where?
-US
-What?
No. To the clinic.
Yes.
Why to the clinic?
-Brother is ill.
-Yes.
-What's wrong with him?
-Piles.
Yes? Yes, I do.
And it's pretty bloody too.
Then get your piles treated.
Why are you following us?
If I catch you following us again
then I'll run a 30-minute feature
on Mathura Live
that Babulal has bloody piles
and it's contagious.
Now get lost.
Slipper.
Couldn't you have said something else?
You should be thankful that I said piles.
Otherwise, I was going to say AIDS.
Shut up. Hurry up.
-Where to?
-After that woman in a red sari.
-What red sari?
-Come on.
-But...
-Hurry up.
A reputed class of Hindu society,
means Agarwal...
Where were you?
If you had taken some more time everyone
would've left for their honeymoon. Come.
Don't ask. Did you register our names?
Yes, I did.
You just need to sign
and collect your token.
They are the ones I was telling you about.
What are their names?
Ranbir Agarwal and Damayanti Agarwal.
-Ranbir.
-Yes.
And I'm Damayanti.
Sign here.
-And their number?
-37.
Take it. Sign it.
And listen.
Put on this headgear so you'll
never have to hide your face again.
Matches are made in heaven.
Yes, matches are made in heaven.
And today 50 such couples will be made.
And Lord Krishna himself
has preordained this.
So, let's begin this interesting
event with His blessings
which is filled with love,
romance and dreams.
Even I couldn't recognize you.
Today we will get you guys married.
Sit.
Bride and groom, take your seats.
-Radhe-Radhe. Come, sit.
-Radhe-Radhe.
-Who is going to perform the rituals?
-I will.
-And who are you?
-I am her brother.
In the name of God,
let's start the rituals.
Everyone, light the lamp
take rice and flowers in your hand.
Radhe-Radhe.
-Live happy.
-Tell us if you need anything.
-Hello, sir.
-Hello, how are you?
Hello. I am Vishnu Trivedi.
I would like to congratulate you two for
coming together in this holy matrimony.
Now you two will come together
in this institution called marriage.
What is your name, son?
He's shy.
Son, tell uncle your name.
-Ranbir Agarwal.
-Son, take off your headgear.
-No!
I can take it off only after the wedding.
Otherwise it's considered ominous.
And what's your name, dear?
-She won't say.
-Why?
Because she can't speak. She is mute.
-She's mute?
-Yes, Priest.
Great.
Marrying a girl who can't speak.
You really are lucky, pal.
Thank you.
Dear, did no one come from your family?
No one.
There is someone.
Her brother.
He was here a minute ago.
He is gone.
I am telling you he is gone.
Hey, Mister. Mister, come here.
You... Come here.
You?
Uncle...
She's your sister?
She's my little sister.
-Little...
-But you're a Muslim.
Then how can you let
your sister get married here?
It doesn't matter.
He's a Muslim.
She's not my real sister,
just someone I call my sister.
You call her your sister.
But she can't speak.
She can't speak?
-Yes, Abbas, your sister can't speak.
-Yes...
If she can't speak,
how does she call you brother?
Well, she uses sign language.
She uses sign language. Show me how.
Using signs.
There it goes.
I know this, Uncle. Hindi.
Nerves.
Handcuffs.
Matchstick.
I will blacken your face.
Rakhi...
-Mr. Trivedi, please.
-Come, Shrikant.
Okay, Uncle.
I think something's fishy.
Fine, Uncle, I'll keep an eye.
Why are you staring at me, Priest?
I am a Muslim, not an alien.
Do your job.
-Mr. Shukla.
-Hello, Uncle, it's Vikas.
Dad's taking a bath.
Vikas, are Guddu and Rashmi at home?
No, Uncle. They are visiting
your family deity's temple.
-They've gone for hours now.
-Family deity?
-But we don't have a family deity.
-What?
But that's where they said they are going.
I have an idea, Uncle,
I'll try calling them.
Their phones are switched off.
Vikas, listen to me carefully.
And answer me correctly.
I am attending the Agarwal
Community Mass Marriage Event.
And that rascal Abbas
is getting his mute sister married.
The boy she's marrying is hiding his face.
But he sounds like Guddu to me.
Father!
Mother!
He's getting married again.
Somebody stop Guddu!
-Go to the mic and say loudly--
-Glory to Goddess?
Uncle!
-Understood?
-Yes, Uncle.
Mr. Guddu Shukla, please come up on stage.
Uncle!
It's him!
Shrikant, stop this wedding.
-Stop all this.
-Stop this charade.
Guddu Shukla, don't you dare move.
The mute girl will stay too.
Why did you turn around?
Let's go, Guddu, he's coming this way.
You don't know my father.
He will bury you alive.
Let's go.
I knew it.
Son-in-law, weren't you
ashamed of doing such a thing?
-Where is Rashmi?
-Tell me.
How dare you marry that Muslim's sister
when my daughter has married you.
My name is Vishnu Trivedi.
I will bury you alive.
-This man's lost his mind.
-Tell me. Where is my daughter?
This man's lost his mind.
He's completely lost his mind.
This is such a cheap thing to do.
Ma'am, maybe you don't
know that he's already married.
You knew everything,
then why didn't you tell her?
What kind of a brother are you?
I will beat you.
Why don't you tell us where Rashmi is?
Tell me!
Uncle, he won't speak up.
Speak up fast otherwise
I'll hit you. Got it?
What's going on here?
Who are you marrying now?
Abbas's sister.
And he knows where my daughter is.
-But he isn't telling us.
-Where is Rashmi? Tell us!
And, Abbas, how can she be your sister?
Your sister is already married. Speak up.
She's like my sister.
A mute sister.
What are you doing, son?
Did someone drug you again?
How many times will you get married?
You got married in a month more than
anyone else did in our entire family.
You're an embarrassment to our family.
He's a spoilt brat.
Stop it, all of you.
I've had enough.
-And if anyone says anything to Guddu--
-She can speak.
I am not mute.
Rashmi?
-You're marrying your own wife again?
-Wife?
I am not his wife yet.
You're are not letting me be.
What on earth is going on, son?
I don't understand.
It's I who don't understand,
Father, as to what's going on.
We've been running
around just to get married.
But all efforts are going in vain.
And I am getting beaten up and thrashed.
I am being called rascal,
pervert and a casanova.
Why? Because we wanted to get married.
Because we fell in love.
That...
I wanted a live-in relationship
before getting married.
Live-in relationship?
You two were in a live-in?
Live-in?
Yes, live-in.
Just like Nazeem Khan. In a live-in.
And like many other young couples
in the country. Live-in.
That means you're not married.
You're still a bachelor.
He's found a new lease of life.
Let's hear them out first.
Stop it, all of you.
Father...
Forget what happened.
We were about to seek
your permission to get married.
Please forget it.
How can we forget it?
What you did is a sin in our religion.
-This is not religion.
-Then what is it?
-It's a topic.
For the elections.
And, Mr. Trivedi,
this is not what the youth wants.
Father, India has the highest
population of youngsters.
More than 700 million.
Imagine 700 million votes.
You never thought about it this way...
which is why you lost
the previous elections.
By a margin of 2300 votes.
To that new guy.
Do you understand what's youth icon?
You lost because the youth was with him.
The youth who wants to live
on its own terms, Father.
The youth these days
knows that religion and caste
are just a topic for the elections.
And your political party, the Culture
Destruction Party--
-That's Protection--
-Shut up.
What protection?
You protect people by blackening
their faces?
Can you even spell the word culture?
The youth these days wants employment.
-Homes.
-Wide roads.
And free Wi-Fi.
Yes, very important.
That's fine.
But, Uncle, do we blacken
their faces or not?
Blacken her face?
She's my daughter.
My daughter.
If any harm comes to her,
I get furious.
You tell me.
Does anyone else know that you two
were in a live-in relationship?
-No.
-Not at all.
-Shrikant.
-Yes, Uncle.
Tear the posters
we had put up against Nazeem Khan.
And no more blackening people's faces.
-But, Uncle--
-Understood?
Go.
And listen.
Please go on stage and restart the mantra.
Guddu Shukla isn't finished yet.
Sir, start.
Yes. Everything is fine.
You and I are made for each other
I am always with you
Your love has floored me
I'm a beauty like
The mountains of Chamba
Your image dwells in my dreamy eyes
-Congratulations.
-What's going on?
Guddu's getting married.
The same boy's getting
married over and over again.
Despite having two bachelors
in the family...
Well, Pappu's date has expired.
But think about me.
Hey, get lost.
Sir, I am a big fan. Can I take a selfie?
Come here.
Is any of the grooms missing?
Can I take his place?
-Talk to Mr. Shukla.
-He is my brother-in-law.
Who is he?
Son-in-law, tell me how do I attract
this young generation towards our party.
SIX MONTHS LATER
"Don't ask a wise man's caste.
Ask about his intelligence.
Value the sword.
Not the scabbard."
-I am Guddu Shukla.
-And I am Rashmi Shukla.
And I think the sun rose
from the west in Mathura today.
Because what you're going to see next
is beyond your imagination.
The Culture Protection Party's
candidate for parliamentary election
Mr. Vishnu Trivedi's election
rally is in progress.
And guess who is campaigning
for his party?
Who?
CHUCK THE HATERS OF LOVERS
WE'LL GIVE YOU Wi-Fi, JOBS AND FLYOVERS
Fair and beautiful
You attitude's mesmerizing
No one's as good looking as you
You're my soft drink bottle
I am your opener
I want to gulp you down
You're my bottle of fizz
You're on fire
I go the gym, I am lean
You speak to me like a machine
You say that you watch Scooby-Dooby Doo
Let it be, don't have to say I love you
Open the bottle
Let it flow freely in the alleys
Everyone's gonna say you're coca-cola
Coca...
Don't mistake me for a bottle of fizz
I am a bottle of whiskey
One sip is all you need
To get you high
There's no tasting
There's no stopping
Just gulp me down in one go
You're my bottle of fizz
You're on fire
Come
Come and quench your thirst
Come and drive my tiredness away
You're my bottle of fizz
You're on fire
Spread this news everywhere
Put posters up on every wall
A boy and a girl...
Are deeply in love
I searched everywhere for love
But once I found you, I was relieved
And now that we're together
Let's go far away
I hope we don't...
Get stuck in this world
Newspapers are old, baby
Post this news online
I am your sweetheart and you are my muse
Take my credit card and you better choose
Destination wedding
And honeymoon on a cruise
These days our love's a hot news
Everyone knows but I am not sorry
Your mom's got no worry
I am your father's old age pension
Take all the attention
Just don't go crazy
Yeah!